[
    {
        "description": "A WISE MAGE.", 
        "health": "WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I CAN HELP.", 
        "keyword_1": "HELP", 
        "keyword_2": "RIDD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE RIDDLE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "IF THE EIGHT\nPHILOSOPHIES OF\nAVATARHOOD\nCOMBINE INTO AND\nARE MADE FROM\nTRUTH, LOVE\n& COURAGE...", 
        "name": "JOSHUA", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "MORE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "OH.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHAT ONE THING\nCREATES AND IS\nCREATED BY ALL\nTRUTHS, ALL LOVE\n& ALL COURAGE?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A FAIR MAIDEN.", 
        "health": "FINE THANKS.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I CAN HELP THEE.", 
        "keyword_1": "HELP", 
        "keyword_2": "ONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "SEEK YE TO KNOW\nHOW THE EIGHT\nVIRTUES FORM\nINTO THE THREE\nPRINCIPLES.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SEEK YE TO KNOW\nWHAT ONE THING\nTHE THREE\nPRINCIPLES OF\nVIRTUE COMBINE\nINTO!", 
        "name": "JULIET", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "KNOW YE THIS?", 
        "question_no_answer": "SEEK IT!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "NOW THE ONE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A DANCING\nJESTER.", 
        "health": "PERFECTLY HOPPY!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "TO ENTERTAIN.", 
        "keyword_1": "JEST", 
        "keyword_2": "BARD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A JESTER NEEDS\nA GOOD BARD!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "OUR BARD IS\nVERY GOOD.", 
        "name": "JESTER TWIN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU LIKE\nTHE MUSIC?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A SHAME, WE DO!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN YOU SHOULD\nGO TO BRITAIN\nFOR THERE LIVES\nTHE BEST!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BURLY GUARD.", 
        "health": "GREAT!", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I GUARD THE\nCASTLE AND MY\nLIEGE!", 
        "keyword_1": "GUAR", 
        "keyword_2": "LIEGE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A GUARD MUST\nBE A VALIANT\nWARRIOR!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I SERVE\nLORD BRITISH!", 
        "name": "A GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU THE\nMOST VALIANT\nWARRIOR?", 
        "question_no_answer": "STILL FLEE NOT\nFROM BATTLE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN THOU SHOULD\nBE A GUARD!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A PERSON WITH\nA WHITE HAT.", 
        "health": "WELL... ALL BUT\nMY FINGER,\nWHICH I CUT!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM THE CHEF.", 
        "keyword_1": "FOOD", 
        "keyword_2": "COOK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "FOOD, GLORIOUS\nFOOD, TO COOK IS\nMY LIFE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "COOKING IS A\nPRACTICED ART.", 
        "name": "LE CHEF", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DO YOU EAT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN THOU\nMUST BE A\nSPIRITUALIST!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN THOU SHOULD\nTRY MY SOUP!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A REAPER.", 
        "health": "NOT SO GOOD,\nNO ONE TO EAT\nIN HERE!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I KILL\nADVENTURERS!", 
        "keyword_1": "KILL", 
        "keyword_2": "THING", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THERE IS A THING\nWHICH CAN KILL\nMANY!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "KNOWLEDGE OF IT\nIS FOUND AT\nBUCCANEER'S DEN!", 
        "name": "A REAPER", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "WILL YOU SEEK\nTHIS THING?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN THOU MUST\nBE STUPID.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "IT BRINGS\nGREAT POWER!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 32
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A RAGGED SOUL.", 
        "health": "VERY POOR.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I HAVE NONE.", 
        "keyword_1": "CRIM", 
        "keyword_2": "PRIS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "CRIME IS AN\nEVIL THING!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "HERE I PAY FOR\nMY CRIMES!", 
        "name": "A NAMELESS\nPRISONER", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ARE YOU A\nPIRATE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I HOPE THAT\nTHIS IS TRUE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "YOU MAY NEVER\nCOMPLETE THY\nQUESTS, FOR EVIL\nMAKES NOT AN\nAVATAR!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WISE MAGE.", 
        "health": "I AM OLD,\nVERY OLD....", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM HERE\nTO HELP THEE.", 
        "keyword_1": "HELP", 
        "keyword_2": "CASTLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "SEEK HELP IN\nTHE CASTLES!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SEEK:\nTHE LYCAEUM,\nEMPATH ABBEY,\nSERPENT'S\nCASTLE!", 
        "name": "ZORIN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU\nGO HITHER?", 
        "question_no_answer": "ALAS.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "FIND THEREIN ALL\nNAMED ANTOS AND\nASK OF THE BELL,\nBOOK, AND\nCANDLE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BURLY GUARD.", 
        "health": "COULDN'T BE\nBETTER!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I GUARD THE\nCASTLE AND ALL\nWITHIN.", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "CAST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I GUARD THE\nCASTLE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE CASTLE IS\nFAIR AND STRONG!", 
        "name": "A GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DO YOU SEEK\nLORD BRITISH?", 
        "question_no_answer": "HE WILL AID\nYOU IF YOU\nARE IN NEED!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "HE IS ON THE\nUPPER LEVEL IN\nTHE THRONE ROOM.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "WATER.", 
        "health": "FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I HOLD A SECRET.", 
        "keyword_1": "SECR", 
        "keyword_2": "ALTAR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "TO WHAT?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THERE ARE THREE\nALTAR ROOMS\nWHICH CONNECT\nTHE BOTTOM\nLEVELS OF ALL\nEIGHT DUNGEONS!", 
        "name": "WATER", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "MORE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "OH.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "IF THE CORRECT\nCOLORS OF STONES\nARE USED IN THE\nALTARS, A KEY OF\nTHREE PARTS CAN\nBE GAINED!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SHEPHERDESS\nBOTH STRONG\nAND BEAUTIFUL.", 
        "health": "WELL.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I WATCH\nTHE WATER.", 
        "keyword_1": "WATER", 
        "keyword_2": "PEACE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "IT BRINGS\nME PEACE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I COME FROM\nA PROUD CITY.", 
        "name": "SHAWN", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "ART THOU PROUD?", 
        "question_no_answer": "MY TOWNE WAS\nDESTROYED FOR\nITS PRIDE. THE\nRUINS LIE ON AN\nISLE AT LAT-K'J\"\nLONG-L'L\"!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "HMMM.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "AN INJURED\nFIGHTER.", 
        "health": "I HAVE A\nGRIEVOUS WOUND.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I FIGHT FOR\nMY COUNTRY.", 
        "keyword_1": "WOUND", 
        "keyword_2": "COUN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "DEEP.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "BRITANNIA.", 
        "name": "SEESHA", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "FIGHT YE FOR\nBRITANNIA?", 
        "question_no_answer": "HMM.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN SEEK OUT\nTHE SMITH NAMED\nZIRCON IN MINOC\nFOR HE MADE THE\nMYSTIC ARMS,\nONLY THEY WILL\nSAVE THEE IN THE\nABYSS!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BOUNCING\nJESTER.", 
        "health": "GOOD, THANKS.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM THE ROYAL\nJESTER", 
        "keyword_1": "JEST", 
        "keyword_2": "CLUE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WELCOME UNTO\nTHE CASTLE\nBRITANNIA!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SPEAK YE UNTO\nTHE WATERS OF\nTHE WELL AND ASK\nOF ALTARS!", 
        "name": "CHUCKLES", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU\nAN ANKH?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN WHY ART\nTHOU HERE?", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN ENTER\nIN PEACE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A GUARD.", 
        "health": "EXCELLENT", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "A GUARD", 
        "keyword_1": "GUAR", 
        "keyword_2": "TREA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WE GUARD THE\nCASTLE AND ITS\nTREASURES.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THAT IS NOT\nYOUR BUSINESS.", 
        "name": "A GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DO YOU MEAN\nTO STEAL?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN PLEASE\nLEAVE AT ONCE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I BELIEVE YOU\nWILL FIND THAT\nAN UNFRUITFUL\nVENTURE.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SOLEMN RANGER.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEARCH FOR\nTHE INNER LIGHT.", 
        "keyword_1": "LIGHT", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRI", 
        "keyword_response_1": "SEEK INNER LIGHT\nIN THE SHRINES!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "RUNES ARE NEEDED\nTO ENTER\nSHRINES!", 
        "name": "SHEILA", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU KNOW\nOF MANTRA?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THE MANTRA ARE\nCHANTS NEEDED\nTO FOCUS THY\nTHOUGHTS WHILE\nMEDITATING.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A GRIM SHEPHERD.", 
        "health": "I AM FINE, BUT\nTHOU MUST\nGO BACK!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM HERE\nTO WARN THEE!", 
        "keyword_1": "WARN", 
        "keyword_2": "PERIL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "AHEAD LIES A\nPERILOUS PLACE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "ONCE THOU ENTERS\nTHOU MAY NOT\nRETURN WHENCE\nTHEE CAME!", 
        "name": "LANDRI", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU GO ON?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THAT IS GOOD.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN THOU ART\nDOOMED!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A STATELY BARON.", 
        "health": "VERY WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I RULE THIS\nPROVINCE.", 
        "keyword_1": "PROV", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "MY LADY BETH CAN\nTELL THEE MORE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I KNOW BUT\nONE OF THREE\nSYLLABLES.", 
        "name": "ROBERT FRASIER", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU WISH\nTO KNOW IT NOW?", 
        "question_no_answer": "PERHAPS\nANOTHER TIME.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "IT IS 'VER'!\nSEEK YE NOW THE\nOTHER PARTS!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A CHARMING LADY.", 
        "health": "WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I RULE WITH\nMY LORD.", 
        "keyword_1": "RULE", 
        "keyword_2": "PROV", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THIS PROVINCE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "OUR PEOPLE\nBELIEVE IN TRUTH\nAS A WAY OF LIFE\nAND LIVE IT TO\nTHE FULLEST!", 
        "name": "BETH FRASIER", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nSEEK TRUTH?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN THOU SHALT\nNOT FIND IT!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN MAY THOU\nFIND IT!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SLEEPY GUARD.", 
        "health": "VERY SLEEPY.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "GUARD THE GATE,\nGUARD THE BARON,\nGUARD THE\nBARONESS, WATCH\nTHE TOWERS....", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "HOURS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I HAVE BEEN HERE\nFOR HOURS!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "YES, MANY HOURS!", 
        "name": "A GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "SEE WHY\nI'M TIRED?", 
        "question_no_answer": "BUM!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "IT'S HARD WORK\nAND LONG HOURS\nIN THE BARONIAL\nGUARD!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 14
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WISE OLD SAGE.", 
        "health": "MY BONES ACHE\nBUT MY MIND\nIS SHARP!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM AN OLD\nWIZARD, BUT HAVE\nMUCH TO SHOW!", 
        "keyword_1": "SHOW", 
        "keyword_2": "TELE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "HERE IN MY\nTELESCOPE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SEARCH THERE BY\nTHE END, THOU\nSHALT FIND\nA KNOB.", 
        "name": "PALAMAR", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nSEE WHERE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "LOOK!!!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "SET THE DIAL AND\nTHOU SHALT SEE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "AN OLD DRUID,\nWHO LOOKS\nSTRANGELY\nFAMILIAR.", 
        "health": "OLD AND FRAIL,\nI'VE SEEN MANY\nQUESTS!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I HOLD GREAT\nKNOWLEDGE.", 
        "keyword_1": "KNOW", 
        "keyword_2": "BOOK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WHAT IS IT\nYOU SEEK?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SEEK YE THE BOOK\nOF TRUTH WHERE\nOTHER BOOKS LIE.", 
        "name": "FATHER ANTOS", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU ON\nTHE QUEST?", 
        "question_no_answer": "OH.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "MAY THOU\nSUCCEED!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BRAWNY GUARD.", 
        "health": "BIT TIRED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I GUARD THE\nTHRONE ROOM.", 
        "keyword_1": "THRONE", 
        "keyword_2": "TRUTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THRONE OF TRUTH!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THERE ARE FOUR\nTOWNES THAT\nFOLLOW THE\nPRINCIPLE OF\nTRUTH.", 
        "name": "JON", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "KNOW WHICH?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THERE ARE\nEIGHT POSSIBLE\nCOMBINATIONS OF\nTHE THREE\nPRINCIPLES,\nTHERE ARE EIGHT\nCITIES!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL MAGE\nWEARING STRANGE\nARMOUR.", 
        "health": "WELL!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I ADVISE.", 
        "keyword_1": "ADVI", 
        "keyword_2": "ARMOUR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THOU WOULD BE\nWELL ADVISED TO\nVISIT THE SEER\nOFTEN!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I WEAR\nMYSTIC ARMOUR.", 
        "name": "SCATU", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU A\nPARTIAL AVATAR?", 
        "question_no_answer": "ALAS.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHEN THOU ART 8\nPARTS AVATAR,\nSEEK ZIRCON IN\nMINOC AND ASK OF\nMYSTICS!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SHORT DRUID.", 
        "health": "WHY I AM FINE,\nYOU TOO I HOPE.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "RESEARCH", 
        "keyword_1": "RESE", 
        "keyword_2": "JUST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I AM LOOKING FOR\nTHE BOOK OF\nJUSTICE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "IT MUST BE HERE\nSOMEWHERE!", 
        "name": "ESTRO", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU NEVER\nCOMMITTED *ANY*\nCRIME!?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN SPEAK TO\nTHE JUDGE IN\nYEW!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I BELIEVE THOU\nART BOASTING\nA LIE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A STATELY\nWIZARD.", 
        "health": "VERY WELL,\nTHANKS!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "TO WELCOME THEE!", 
        "keyword_1": "WELC", 
        "keyword_2": "FOUR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "YES, WELCOME TO\nTHE LYCAEUM, THE\nKEEP OF TRUTH!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE DUNGEON\nALTAR ROOMS NEED\n4 STONES EACH!", 
        "name": "TYMUS", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "KNOW YE HOW MANY\nCITIES FOLLOW\nTHE PRINCIPLES\nOF TRUTH?", 
        "question_no_answer": "TRAVEL AND\nLEARN!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "HOW MANY?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A PERSON LOST\nIN THOUGHT.", 
        "health": "I AM IN A\nMEDITATIVE\nSTATE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEEK TO\nKNOW TRUTH.", 
        "keyword_1": "TRUTH", 
        "keyword_2": "MEDI", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE PRINCIPLE\nUPON WHICH I\nMEDITATE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "MEDITATE AT EACH\nSHRINE FOR 1, 2\nAND 3 CYCLES,\nTHEN SHALT THOU\nKNOW THE PATHS\nOF GOODNESS!", 
        "name": "A TRUTH\nSEEKER", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "AN INJURED\nWARRIOR.", 
        "health": "MY WOUNDS ARE\nGRIEVOUS!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "NONE NOW!", 
        "keyword_1": "WARR", 
        "keyword_2": "WOUNDS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "NO MORE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I LOST IN A\nDUNGEON ALTAR\nROOM!", 
        "name": "A FIGHTER", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU\nSEEN ONE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEY CONNECT THE\nDUNGEONS UNTO\nEACH OTHER!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "NOTICE THAT\nEACH OF THE\nTHREE ROOMS\nCONNECT TO FOUR\nDUNGEONS EACH!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL AGILE\nMAN.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM THE\nLIBRARIAN.", 
        "keyword_1": "LIBR", 
        "keyword_2": "TRUTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "HEREIN IS THE\nLARGEST STORE\nOF KNOWLEDGE IN\nBRITANNIA EXCEPT\nTHE CODEX!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "LOOK UNDER 'T'.", 
        "name": "LORD TERENCE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU LOOKING\nFOR A PARTICULAR\nBOOK?", 
        "question_no_answer": "FEEL FREE\nTO BROWSE.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHICH BOOK?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A FLIGHTY\nJESTER.", 
        "health": "UNHAPPY.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "TO ENTERTAIN!", 
        "keyword_1": "ENTER", 
        "keyword_2": "UNHAPP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "AH, NOT NOW.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "BECAUSE MY\nFRIEND CHUCKLES\nWON'T TELL ME\nHIS SECRET!", 
        "name": "ZAJAC", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU KNOW\nCHUCKLES?", 
        "question_no_answer": "HE LIVES IN\nTHE CASTLE\nBRITANNIA ASK\nHIM OF HIS CLUE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHY DOST THOU\nNOT ASK HIM FOR\nHIS CLUE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A STRONG GUARD.", 
        "health": "VERY GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "TO WATCH THE\nTREASURES.", 
        "keyword_1": "TREAS", 
        "keyword_2": "VALUE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE TREASURES\nARE OF GREAT\nVALUE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "YES, MUCH GOLD.", 
        "name": "CATRIONA", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU INTEND\nTO STEAL?", 
        "question_no_answer": "GOOD, YOU HAD\nME WORRIED!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I SHAN'T STOP\nTHEE.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A NOBLE WIZARD.", 
        "health": "GOOD ENOUGH.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I TEACH MAGICAL\nSPELLS.", 
        "keyword_1": "SPELLS", 
        "keyword_2": "RECALL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I HAVE A\nSPECIALTY!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "YES,\nRESURRECTION\nIT TAKES: ASH,\nGINSENG, GARLIC,\nSILK, BLOODMOSS,\nAND MANDRAKE!", 
        "name": "NIGEL, AT THY\nSERVICE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU KNOW\nWHAT IT IS?", 
        "question_no_answer": "SORRY.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHAT DO I CALL\nTHE SPELL?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A PITIFUL\nBEGGAR.", 
        "health": "I AM COLD\nAND SICK!\nOH... PLEASE...", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SIT AND BEG\nOH... PLEASE...", 
        "keyword_1": "BEG", 
        "keyword_2": "SICK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "YES, PLEASE\nGIVE ME MONEY!\nOH... PLEASE...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I HAVE THE\nBLACK PLAGUE!", 
        "name": "SHYLOCK THE MEEK", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU\nHELP ME?\nOH... PLEASE...", 
        "question_no_answer": "OH... PLEASE...", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "OH... PLEASE...", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A STATELY BARON.", 
        "health": "VERY WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I RULE THIS\nPROVINCE.", 
        "keyword_1": "PROV", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "MY LADY MARCY\nCAN TELL THEE\nMORE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I KNOW BUT\nONE OF THREE\nSYLLABLES.", 
        "name": "LORD ROBERT", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU WISH\nTO KNOW IT NOW?", 
        "question_no_answer": "PERHAPS\nANOTHER TIME.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "IT IS 'AMO'!\nSEEK YE NOW THE\nOTHER PARTS!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A CHARMING LADY.", 
        "health": "WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I RULE WITH\nMY LORD.", 
        "keyword_1": "RULE", 
        "keyword_2": "PROV", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THIS PROVINCE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "OUR PEOPLE\nBELIEVE IN LOVE\nAS A WAY OF LIFE\nAND LIVE IT TO\nTHE FULLEST!", 
        "name": "LADY MARCY", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nSEEK LOVE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN THOU SHALT\nNOT FIND IT!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN MAYST THOU\nFIND IT!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A LOVELY LADY.", 
        "health": "OVERWORKED!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM A LADY\nIN WAITING.", 
        "keyword_1": "LADY", 
        "keyword_2": "HORN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I SERVE MARCY.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THERE IS A\nPALADIN BY THE\nNAME OF MALCHOR.\nHE CAN LEAD THEE\nTO THE SILVER\nHORN!", 
        "name": "SUZANNA", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "ART THOU ALLOWED\nTO BE IN HERE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THOU SHOULD\nLEAVE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I DOUBT IT!\nTHOU SHOULD\nLEAVE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 40
    }, 
    {
        "description": "AN ANKH.", 
        "health": "I EXIST.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I RESONATE\nTHOUGHTS.", 
        "keyword_1": "RESON", 
        "keyword_2": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WHAT ARE THY\nTHOUGHTS?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SEEK YE THE\nCANDLE OF LOVE\nFOR ONLY WITH IT\nAND TWO OTHER\nPARTS MIGHT THOU\nENTER THE ABYSS!", 
        "name": "LIFE", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nHAVE IT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "ASK THE BARD\nBEYOND THE\nSECRET PASSAGE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A GUARD.", 
        "health": "FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I GUARD THE\nPASSAGES.", 
        "keyword_1": "PASS", 
        "keyword_2": "DANG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THERE IS\nNO DANGER.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "WELL NOT\nCOMPARED TO A\nDUNGEON ALTAR\nROOM!", 
        "name": "THE PASS GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU SOLVED\nTHE ALTARS?", 
        "question_no_answer": "FROM THEM A\nTHREE PART KEY\nIS GAINED,\nNEEDED TO ENTER\nTHE CHAMBER OF\nTHE CODEX!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A GUARD.", 
        "health": "TOP NOTCH.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "A GATE GUARD", 
        "keyword_1": "GATE", 
        "keyword_2": "ABBEY", 
        "keyword_response_1": "TO THE ABBEY.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "HERE, IN THE OAK\nGROVE MANY FIND\nTHE MEANING OF\nPEACE AND LOVE!", 
        "name": "A GATE GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU\nSATURATED WITH\nLOVE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "VISIT THE SMALL\nSHRINE WITHIN\nTHE ABBEY!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN THOU NEED\nNOT BE HERE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A YOUNG BARD\nPLAYING A LUTE.", 
        "health": "PRETTY GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM A BARD,\nI SING SONGS.", 
        "keyword_1": "SONGS", 
        "keyword_2": "CAND", 
        "keyword_response_1": "OH, ALL TYPES.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE CANDLE OF\nLOVE IS FOUND IN\nA SECRET PLACE\nHIDDEN OFF\nLOCK LAKE!", 
        "name": "DEREK THE BARD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU LIKE\nTHIS ONE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "ALAS,\nIT WAS NEW.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THANKS, I JUST\nWROTE IT!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SMALL BUT\nSTATELY CHILD.", 
        "health": "VERY WELL,\nTHANK YOU!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I WELCOME THEE\nUNTO THE ABBEY!", 
        "keyword_1": "GROVE", 
        "keyword_2": "OAK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A GROVE OF OAK.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THERE FOUR\nPROFESSION TYPES\nSEEK TRUTH!", 
        "name": "CHINUP", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU HERE IN\nSEARCH OF LOVE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "PERHAPS THEN THE\nOAK GROVE.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "PERHAPS THEN THE\nOAK GROVE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL WOMAN.", 
        "health": "GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I COUNSEL THOSE\nWHO ENTER\nTHE GROVE.", 
        "keyword_1": "COUN", 
        "keyword_2": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "HEREIN THOU MAY\nFIND INSIGHTS\nINTO LOVE,\nWITHIN THYSELF\nOR THE OTHERS\nHERE IN THE\nGROVE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "ASK THE OTHERS.", 
        "name": "DIANE", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "ART THOU THE\nMOST LOVING\nPERSON?", 
        "question_no_answer": "STRIVE FOR LOVE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "DOUBTFUL!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SOLEMN BARD.", 
        "health": "FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I RELATE LOVE\nAND COMPASSION.", 
        "keyword_1": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_2": "COMP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WHEN THE THREE\nCOMBINE IN EIGHT\nWAYS LOVE ALONE\nIS COMPASSION.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "OF THE\nEIGHT AVATAR\nATTRIBUTES\nCOMPASSION IS\nDERIVED FROM\nLOVE ALONE.", 
        "name": "BENJAMIN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU WELL?", 
        "question_no_answer": "TOO BAD...", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "VERY GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A DRUID,\nLOST IN THOUGHT.", 
        "health": "FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I PONDER LOVE\nAND JUSTICE.", 
        "keyword_1": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_2": "JUST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WHEN THREE BUILD\nEIGHT, TRUTH\nTEMPERED BY LOVE\nBECOMES JUSTICE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "JUSTICE IS ONE\nOF THE EIGHT\nAVATAR VIRTUES\nAND DERIVES FROM\nTRUTH AND LOVE.", 
        "name": "DEIRDRE", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "ART THOU?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I SEE.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "MOST GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A HEARTY TINKER.", 
        "health": "FINE", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM THINKING OF\nLOVE'S PART IN\nSACRIFICE.", 
        "keyword_1": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_2": "SACR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "LOVE OF OTHERS\nAND THE COURAGE\nTO FACE EVEN\nDEATH IS\nSELF-SACRIFICE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SACRIFICE IS\nBUILT UPON THE\nMOTIVE OF LOVE\nAND THE ABILITY\nOF COURAGE.", 
        "name": "THOMAS", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "THYSELF?", 
        "question_no_answer": "SHAME.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SOLEMN\nRANGER.", 
        "health": "MOST WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I FOLLOW THE\nSPIRITUAL PATH.", 
        "keyword_1": "SPIR", 
        "keyword_2": "BEING", 
        "keyword_response_1": "MY SPIRITUALITY\nIS NOT A\nRELIGION, BUT A\nSEARCHING TO\nKNOW AND IMPROVE\nMY OWN INNER\nBEING.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "MY BEING IS\nBASED ON MY OWN\nTRUTH, LOVE AND\nCOURAGE.", 
        "name": "LASTRO", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "AND THEE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "SO SAD.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A MUMBLING\nBEGGAR.", 
        "health": "NOT SO GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEEK SALVATION", 
        "keyword_1": "MUMB", 
        "keyword_2": "SALV", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE...ANKH...\nSPOKE TO ME!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I AM BUT A POOR\nDESTITUTE BEGGAR\nI HAVE NOTHING!", 
        "name": "HUMLOCK", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "WILL YOU GIVE ME\nSOME MONEY?", 
        "question_no_answer": "BUT I AM IN\nMOST DIRE NEED!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I WOULD BE SOOOO\nGRATEFUL....", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BOLD PALADIN.", 
        "health": "JUST NOW\nFULLY HEALED!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SOLVE QUESTS", 
        "keyword_1": "QUESTS", 
        "keyword_2": "HORN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "MY LAST QUEST\nTOOK ME NEAR\nSPIRITWOOD.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SOME SAY THAT\nTHE SILVER HORN\nIS BURIED ON A\nSMALL ISLE OFF\nTHE TIP OF\nSPIRITWOOD.", 
        "name": "MALCHOR", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU\nON A QUEST?", 
        "question_no_answer": "OH.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "BEST OF LUCK\nTO THEE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WISE DRUID.", 
        "health": "I AM GETTING OLD\nAND FRAIL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I HOLD GREAT\nWISDOM.", 
        "keyword_1": "WISDOM", 
        "keyword_2": "CANDLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WHAT DOST THOU\nASK OF ME?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THOU DOST NEED\nTHE CANDLE OF\nLOVE TO ENTER\nTHE ABYSS.", 
        "name": "BROTHER ANTOS", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nKNOW WHERE\nTO FIND IT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "MEDITATE ON LOVE\nAT OUR SHRINE.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "VERY GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A STATELY BARON.", 
        "health": "VERY WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I RULE THIS\nPROVINCE.", 
        "keyword_1": "PROV", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "YES, THESE\nISLANDS AND\nMUCH MORE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I KNOW BUT\nONE OF THREE\nSYLLABLES-'COR'.", 
        "name": "SENTRI", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU KNOW\nTHE FOUR CITIES\nOF COURAGE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEY ARE JHELOM,\nMINOC, TRINSIC\nAND SKARA BRAE.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "VERY GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A VERY\nBIG GUARD.", 
        "health": "VERY STRONG!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "GUARD THE GATES,\nOF COURSE.", 
        "keyword_1": "GATES", 
        "keyword_2": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THESE ARE THE\nGATES TO SERPENT\nCASTLE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "GUARD, WATCH,\nPROTECT.", 
        "name": "THE GATE GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU HERE TO\nFIND COURAGE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN PERHAPS TO\nBECOME A GUARD!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN THOU ART AT\nTHE RIGHT PLACE.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WOUNDED\nSAILOR.", 
        "health": "I ALONE SURVIVED\nTHE SHIPWRECK.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM A SAILOR.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHIP", 
        "keyword_2": "WHEEL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE H.M.S. CAPE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SHE WENT DOWN IN\nTHE DEEP WATERS\nOF THE BAY IN\nTHE CAPE OF\nHEROES!", 
        "name": "LASSORN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "EVER HEARD\nOF HER?", 
        "question_no_answer": "SHE WAS A\nMIGHTY VESSEL!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "SHE WAS A\nMIGHTY VESSEL!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SEASONED\nFIGHTER.", 
        "health": "JUST HEALED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I FIGHT FOR\nBRITANNIA!", 
        "keyword_1": "ABYSS", 
        "keyword_2": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE GREAT\nSTYGIAN ABYSS\nHOLDS THE CODEX\nOF ULTIMATE\nWISDOM!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I KNOW LITTLE.", 
        "name": "ROARK", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU WELL?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THOU HAST COME\nTO THE RIGHT\nPLACE.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN STRIVE TO\nFIND THE SECRETS\nOF THE ABYSS.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A RANGER\nENGROSSED IN\nTRAINING.", 
        "health": "EXCELLENT.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM TRAINING!", 
        "keyword_1": "TRAIN", 
        "keyword_2": "DUNG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I TRAIN SO THAT\nI MIGHT SURVIVE\nTHE DUNGEONS!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I PLAN TO\nCONQUER THE\nSECRET OF THE\nALTAR ROOMS.", 
        "name": "A RANGER", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU?", 
        "question_no_answer": "WIMP.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "ASK OUR TEACHER\nABOUT THE ROOMS\nFOR SHE KNOWS\nMUCH!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "THE TRAINING\nMASTER.", 
        "health": "PRIME.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I TRAIN WARRIORS\nTO FIGHT WITH\nCOURAGE!", 
        "keyword_1": "TRAIN", 
        "keyword_2": "ROOM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "TRAIN WELL AND\nTHY COURAGE CAN\nGROW WITH\nCONFIDENCE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "IN THE ALTAR\nROOM OF COURAGE\nUSE THE RED,\nORANGE, PURPLE\nAND WHITE\nSTONES!", 
        "name": "SHYRA", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU TRAIN?", 
        "question_no_answer": "PITY.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "BRAVO!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A STERN GUARD.", 
        "health": "MOST GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I GUARD OUR LORD", 
        "keyword_1": "LORD", 
        "keyword_2": "CAST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "SENTRI RULES\nTHIS CASTLE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THIS CASTLE IS\nBUILT ON\nCOURAGE.", 
        "name": "A BARONIAL GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU WISH\nAN AUDIENCE\nWITH SENTRI?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN DO NOT\nDISTURB HIM.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GRANTED, ENTER.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BURLY GUARD.", 
        "health": "EXCELLENT.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "WE GUARD OUR\nLORD'S TREASURE.", 
        "keyword_1": "TREAS", 
        "keyword_2": "DUNG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THIS TREASURE IS\nNOT FOR THEE", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SEEK OUT DURHAM\nFOR KNOWLEDGE OF\nDUNGEONS.", 
        "name": "A TREASURE GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU INTEND\nTO STEAL\nOUR LORD'S\nTREASURE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "WISE MOVE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "FOOL!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BOLD FIGHTER.", 
        "health": "QUITE WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I FIGHT WITH\nCOURAGE!", 
        "keyword_1": "COUR", 
        "keyword_2": "BELL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "COURAGE MAKES\nKINGS OUT OF\nKNAVES!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE BELL OF\nCOURAGE LIES AT\nTHE BOTTOM OF A\nDEEP WELL AT SEA\nFOUND AT\nLAT-N'A\"\nLONG-L'A\"", 
        "name": "GARAM", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN TRAIN!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL FIGHTER.", 
        "health": "FAIRLY WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I QUEST\nFOR GLORY!", 
        "keyword_1": "QUEST", 
        "keyword_2": "DUNG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I FEEL THAT WHEN\nON A QUEST MY\nLIFE HAS\nPURPOSE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE ALTAR ROOM\nOF COURAGE GIVES\nTHE THIRD PART\nOF A KEY.", 
        "name": "DURHAM", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU ON\nA QUEST?", 
        "question_no_answer": "WHAT A LOSS.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN THY LIFE\nHAS MEANING!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BUXOM GUARD.", 
        "health": "SO FAR, SO GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I GUARD THIS\nPASSAGE.", 
        "keyword_1": "GARAM", 
        "keyword_2": "DURHAM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "HE IS IN THE\nWEST CHAMBER.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "HE IS IN THE\nEAST CHAMBER.", 
        "name": "LORI", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "ART THOU LOOKING\nFOR SOMEONE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN BE ON\nTHY WAY!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHO?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A HANDSOME\nGUARD.", 
        "health": "SO FAR, SO GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I GUARD THIS\nPASSAGE.", 
        "keyword_1": "GARAM", 
        "keyword_2": "DURHAM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "HE IS IN THE\nWEST CHAMBER.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "HE IS IN THE\nEAST CHAMBER.", 
        "name": "SAMUEL", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU LOOKING\nFOR SOMEONE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN BE ON\nTHY WAY!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHO?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A DESTITUTE,\nSTINKING BEGGAR.", 
        "health": "I'VE LOST\nA HAND!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I CANNOT WORK.", 
        "keyword_1": "HAND", 
        "keyword_2": "ORBS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "IT WAS EATEN\nBY A ZORN.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "AN ORB OF BLUE\nLIGHT WILL RAISE\nTHY STRENGTH,\nDEXTERITY OR\nINTELLIGENCE,\nBUT AT A COST!", 
        "name": "RODERICK", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU GIVE\nME GOLD?", 
        "question_no_answer": "STINGY!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THOU ART KIND.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WISE DRUID.", 
        "health": "WELL ENOUGH.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I HAVE IMPORTANT\nINFORMATION.", 
        "keyword_1": "INFORM", 
        "keyword_2": "BELL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "ON WHAT SUBJECT?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE BELL OF\nCOURAGE IS\nNEEDED TO ENTER\nTHE ABYSS.", 
        "name": "SISTER ANTOS", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nHAVE IT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN ASK THE\nFIGHTER GARAM\nFOR HE KNOWS\nWHERE IT LIES!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "VERY GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SPINY NIXIE!", 
        "health": "NICE AND WET!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SWIM THE SEAS!", 
        "keyword_1": "SEAS", 
        "keyword_2": "SHIPS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THERE ARE MANY\nSHIPS AT THE\nBOTTOM!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A SURVIVOR WOULD\nKNOW WHERE TO\nSEARCH.", 
        "name": "NOXUM", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU\nHEARD OF THE\nH.M.S. CAPE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A GREAT SHIP!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "SHE HAD A\nMAGICAL WHEEL\nTHAT WOULD\nSTRENGTHEN HER\nHULL!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BEAUTIFUL\nPALADIN!", 
        "health": "VERY WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I WELCOME THEE\nUNTO SERPENT\nCASTLE!", 
        "keyword_1": "SENTRI", 
        "keyword_2": "VISIT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "HE IS THE LORD\nHERE, TAKE THE\nWEST PASSAGE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "TAKE THE EAST\nPASSAGE.", 
        "name": "MICHELLE", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "ART THOU WELL?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN THOU SHOULD\nVISIT OUR\nHEALER!", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "VERY GOOD,\nPERHAPS THOU\nSEEKS SENTRI.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A YOUNG MAGE.", 
        "health": "QUITE GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEEK\nADVENTURE!", 
        "keyword_1": "ADVENT", 
        "keyword_2": "QUEST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "YES, I HOPE TO\nGO ON A GREAT\nQUEST!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE QUEST OF THE\nAVATAR IS NOBLE\nINDEED!", 
        "name": "MARIAH", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "ART THOU ON\nA QUEST?", 
        "question_no_answer": "WISH THOU WERE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I WISH I COULD\nJOIN THEE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A STARVING\nJOURNALIST.", 
        "health": "I FEEL FINE...\nIF I COULD JUST\nQUIT SMOKING!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM A WRITER.", 
        "keyword_1": "WRIT", 
        "keyword_2": "SMOK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "IT'S LOW PAID,\nBUT GLAMOROUS!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "COUGH...COUGH...", 
        "name": "TRACIE", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DO YOU SMOKE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "DON'T START!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I CAN TELL\nBY THE SMELL!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A REGAL PALADIN.", 
        "health": "WELL INDEED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SPEAK OF THE\nVIRTUES OF\nHONESTY!", 
        "keyword_1": "HONEST", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A FEW HONEST MEN\nARE BETTER THAN\nNUMBERS!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE MANTRA OF\nTHE SHRINE\nOF HONESTY\nIS 'AHM'.", 
        "name": "CROMWELL", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU STRIVE\nTO BE HONEST?", 
        "question_no_answer": "SHAME!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN YOU WILL\nNEED THE MANTRA.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A MYSTIC WIZARD.", 
        "health": "I'VE BEEN BETTER", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I LIVE AN\nHONEST LIFE.", 
        "keyword_1": "HONEST", 
        "keyword_2": "EVIL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "SPEAK THE TRUTH\nAND SHAME THE\nEVIL FORCES!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "EVIL STILL\nEXISTS IN\nOUR HEARTS\nAND SOULS!", 
        "name": "REBELIAS", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU SEEK\nTO CONQUER THINE\nOWN EVIL?", 
        "question_no_answer": "WRETCH!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THE QUEST OF\nA LIFETIME!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A PLAYFUL CHILD.", 
        "health": "FEELING GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM YOUR\nFRIEND.", 
        "keyword_1": "FRIEND", 
        "keyword_2": "HONEST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "HONEST FRIENDS\nARE FEW!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "MY FRIEND\nWILLIAM KNOWS\nWHERE THE RUNE\nOF HONESTY IS.", 
        "name": "CHRISTEN", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "ART THOU MY\nFRIEND?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I AM SAD.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THAT MAKES\nME HAPPY.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A MEEK SHEPHERD.", 
        "health": "PRETTY GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I AM A SHEPHERD.", 
        "keyword_1": "HUMBLE", 
        "keyword_2": "HUMI", 
        "keyword_response_1": "HUMILITY IS\nNOT DERIVED FROM\nTHE DIRECT\nCOMBINATION OF\nTRUTH, LOVE OR\nCOURAGE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "HUMILITY IS TO\nACT AND BE\nHUMBLE.", 
        "name": "PATRIC THE\nHUMBLE SHEPHERD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU\nTOTALLY HUMBLE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "STRIVE TO BE.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "DOUBTFUL!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A DYING YOUNG\nWIZARD.", 
        "health": "I WILL SOON DIE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM APPRENTICE\nTO THE GREAT\nWIZARD NIGEL!", 
        "keyword_1": "NIGEL", 
        "keyword_2": "DIE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I WILL SOON\nNEED TO USE\nTHE SPELL HE\nCALLS 'RECALL'.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "PASS ON.", 
        "name": "SHAZOM", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU\nMET NIGEL?", 
        "question_no_answer": "HE LIVES AT\nTHE LYCAEUM.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "SEEK HIM OUT FOR\nHE WILL TEACH\nTHEE.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WISE WIZARD.", 
        "health": "GETTING ON.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I CREATE TALES\nOF HONESTY.", 
        "keyword_1": "HONES", 
        "keyword_2": "CORRUP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "REMEMBER, THERE\nIS NO TERROR\nIN THREATS FOR\nI AM STRONG\nIN HONESTY!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "CORRUPTION WINS\nNOT MORE THAN\nHONESTY!", 
        "name": "SHAKESPEARE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU STRIVE\nTO BE HONEST?", 
        "question_no_answer": "FOOL!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "BEWARE\nCORRUPTION!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL MAGE.", 
        "health": "BEEN BETTER.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I STRIVE TO LIVE\nAN HONEST LIFE!", 
        "keyword_1": "HONE", 
        "keyword_2": "TRUTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "AN HONEST SOUL\nNEED REMEMBER\nNO LIES!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "TRUTH IS THE\nROOT OF HONESTY!", 
        "name": "BROWNING", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU\nNEVER LIED?", 
        "question_no_answer": "TRUTH NEVER\nHURTS THE\nTELLER!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THAT SEEMS\nUNLIKELY!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "AN ELDERLY\nWOMAN.", 
        "health": "TIRED, SO TIRED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM AN\nALCHEMIST.", 
        "keyword_1": "ALCHEM", 
        "keyword_2": "REAGEN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I KNOW HOW BEST\nTO MIX REAGENTS!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A SLEEP SPELL\nACTUALLY\nREQUIRES BUT\nONE PART\nSPIDER SILK!", 
        "name": "COSIMA", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU KNOW\nHOW TO BEST MIX\nSPELLS?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THE SECRET'S IN\nTHE REAGENTS!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A HUNCHED,\nINSANE LOOKING\nMAN!", 
        "health": "HEALTH?", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I MOVE THE SUN!", 
        "keyword_1": "SUN", 
        "keyword_2": "MOON", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE MOONS ARE\nMY ENEMIES!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "WHEN I DIE THE\nWORLD WILL END!", 
        "name": "DARANOR", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DO YOU BELIEVE\nMY STORY!?!?...", 
        "question_no_answer": "IDIOT, YOU MUST\nTHINK I AM\nINSANE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN WE MUST\nFELL THE MOONS!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "AN OLD GYPSY.", 
        "health": "I PREDICT I WILL\nBE FINE TODAY!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM A FORTUNE\nTELLER, I READ\nPALMS.", 
        "keyword_1": "PALM", 
        "keyword_2": "FORTUN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "PALMS TELL\nFORTUNES!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "GIVE THY PALM.", 
        "name": "INOO", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU WISH\nTHY DESTINY?", 
        "question_no_answer": "WISE CHOICE.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A GREAT QUEST\nWILL LEAD THEE\nINTO THE ABYSS\nWHERE THE CODEX\nAWAITS!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL MAGE.", 
        "health": "FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I BEAR GREETINGS\nFROM THE FAIR\nCITY OF\nMOONGLOW.", 
        "keyword_1": "INN", 
        "keyword_2": "INJURE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WE HAVE AN\nEXCELLENT INN.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "OUR HEALER IS\nONE OF THE BEST!", 
        "name": "CALABRINI", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU SEEK\nAN INN OR ART\nTHOU INJURED?", 
        "question_no_answer": "PERHAPS, THE\nSHRINE WHICH\nLIES ON AN ISLE\nTO THE NORTH!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHICH?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BOUNCY JESTER.", 
        "health": "VERY GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I EARN AN HONEST\nLIVING, JESTING!", 
        "keyword_1": "HONEST", 
        "keyword_2": "JEST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "HONEST LABOR\nBEARS A LOVELY\nFACE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I LOVE A\nGOOD JEST.", 
        "name": "DEKKER", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THOU ART\nPROBABLY A\nSOURPUSS!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WE OUGHT TO\nEXCHANGE JOKES\nSOMETIME!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A CHILD EATING\nA SANDWICH.", 
        "health": "PRETTY GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "OH, NOT MUCH.", 
        "keyword_1": "SANDW", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "IT'S A PEANUT\nBUTTER AND GRAPE\nJELLY ON LIGHTLY\nTOASTED BREAD!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SEARCH FOR THE\nRUNE OF HONESTY\nBY MARIAH'S\nGOLD!", 
        "name": "WILLIAM", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "WOULDST THOU\nLIKE A BITE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "IT'S AWFUL\nYUMMY!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "YUMMY, HUH!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BATTERED MAGE.", 
        "health": "FADING.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I USED TO SEARCH\nFOR THE BLUE\nSTONE.", 
        "keyword_1": "STONE", 
        "keyword_2": "USE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE STONE OF\nHONESTY IS FOUND\nON AN ALTAR IN\nTHE DUNGEON OF\nDECEIT.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "IT IS USED\nWITHIN THE\nDUNGEON ALTAR\nROOMS AND IN\nTHE ABYSS.", 
        "name": "TYRONE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU\nSEARCH?", 
        "question_no_answer": "HMM.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "KNOW ITS USES!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A CHARMING BARD.", 
        "health": "GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I PLAY FOR\nTHE PEOPLE.", 
        "keyword_1": "PLAY", 
        "keyword_2": "COMP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I PLAY MY LUTE\nAND RECEIVE THE\nGOOD WISHES OF\nTHE PEOPLE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "IF YOU TREAT\nSOMEONE ELSE\nWELL THEN THEY\nWILL HAVE REASON\nTO DO THE SAME.", 
        "name": "IOLO", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DO YOU LIKE\nMY MUSIC?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A SHAME.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I WOULD\nJOIN THEE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A CHARMING\nJESTER.", 
        "health": "VERY WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I DANCE AND\nSING FOR THE\nCHILDREN.", 
        "keyword_1": "DANCE", 
        "keyword_2": "BEGG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "DANCE IS GOOD\nFOR THE SOUL.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "TO GIVE TO A\nBEGGAR SHOWS\nCOMPASSION.", 
        "name": "GWENO", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DO YOU GIVE\nTO THE NEEDY?", 
        "question_no_answer": "ALAS.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "BEGGARS ARE\nTHANKFUL FOR\nSMALL DONATIONS.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SMALL CHILD.", 
        "health": "VERY HAPPY.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "SINGING", 
        "keyword_1": "SING", 
        "keyword_2": "HO EYO", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE SONG GOES:\nHO EYO HE HUM!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "IT MEANS:\nLOVE TO ONE\nAND ALL!", 
        "name": "A CHILD", 
        "pronoun": "THE CHILD", 
        "question": "DO YOU LIKE\nTHE SONG?", 
        "question_no_answer": "TOO BAD.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN HELP US\nSPREAD THE WORD!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A GUARD.", 
        "health": "GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I GUARD THE\nBRIDGE.", 
        "keyword_1": "BRIDGE", 
        "keyword_2": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "ACROSS THE\nBRIDGE OUR\nPEOPLE DANCE\nAND SING!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "YEP.", 
        "name": "A GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "WOULD THOU LIKE\nTO JOIN THEM?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN YOU HAVE\nNO BUSINESS\nACROSS THE\nBRIDGE.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "REMEMBER, AN\nOPEN HEART IS\nTHE FIRST STEP\nON THE PATH TO\nWISDOM!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SPICY WOMAN.", 
        "health": "HEALTHY.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM A\nFIGHTING BARD.", 
        "keyword_1": "BARD", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "BARDS KNOW\nMANY THINGS.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE RUNE OF\nCOMPASSION LIES\nAT THE END OF A\nHALL SOMEWHERE\nIN THIS TOWNE.", 
        "name": "PEPPER", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU SEEK\nSOMETHING?", 
        "question_no_answer": "ALAS, I MAY HAVE\nBEEN ABLE TO\nHELP.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHAT MIGHT\nTHAT BE?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SEASONED\nFIGHTER.", 
        "health": "FAIRLY WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEARCH FOR\nTHE MYSTERY OF\nTHE MAGIC ORBS.", 
        "keyword_1": "ORBS", 
        "keyword_2": "MAGIC", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A ONE-HANDED\nBEGGAR KNOWS\nTHEIR SECRETS!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "MAGIC ORBS.", 
        "name": "THEVEL", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU\nSEEN HIM?", 
        "question_no_answer": "FIND HIM IN\nSERPENT CASTLE\nFOR HE KNOWS OF\nORBS!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "ONLY HE KNOWS\nTHE ORB'S GIFT!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A DRUNKEN\nFIGHTER.", 
        "health": "AND A BOTTLE\nOF...", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "YO HO HO...\nAND A BOTTLE...\nOF RUM...\nHIC...", 
        "keyword_1": "STONE", 
        "keyword_2": "RUM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE YELLOW STONE\nIS IN THE\nDUNGEON\nDESPISE...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "RUM... HIC...", 
        "name": "JOE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "GIVE ME RUM?...", 
        "question_no_answer": "AH, BE A JOE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THANXTH...\nMY FRIEND JOE\nCAN HELP WITH\nTHE STONES...\nHIC...", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BARD IN GREEN.", 
        "health": "SHHH", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "SHHH, I'M\nPLAYING!", 
        "keyword_1": "SHHH", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "YES, SHHH!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE MANTRA FOR\nTHE SHRINE OF\nCOMPASSION\nIS 'MU'!", 
        "name": "CRICKET", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "NOW WILT THOU\nBE QUIET?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I AM GOING TO\nCALL THE GUARDS!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THANKS.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A CHEERFUL\nGUARD.", 
        "health": "I AM FULLY\nHEALED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM A GUARD\nOF COURSE!", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "COMP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WE GUARDS HAVE\nA LOT OF\nCOMPASSION.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "WE ALWAYS SAY:\nLET ALL OTHERS'\nTROUBLES BE AS\nTHINE OWN!", 
        "name": "A GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU KILL\nNON-EVIL\nCREATURES?", 
        "question_no_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THAT DOES NOT\nSHOW COMPASSION!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SMALL CHILD.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM LEARNING\nCOMPASSION.", 
        "keyword_1": "LEARN", 
        "keyword_2": "COMP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE SOLUTION TO\nONES PROBLEMS\nOFTEN LIES IN\nSOLVING OTHERS!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "NEVER CARE SO\nMUCH FOR THYSELF\nTHAT THOU CANNOT\nCARE FOR OTHERS!", 
        "name": "A CHILD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "KNOW YE THE\nMANTRA OF\nCOMPASSION?", 
        "question_no_answer": "ASK CRICKET!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TIRED\nSHEPHERD.", 
        "health": "GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I WATCH OVER\nTHE CHILDREN.", 
        "keyword_1": "CHILD", 
        "keyword_2": "COMP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "IT TAKES A\nGOOD DEAL OF\nCOMPASSION TO\nDEAL WITH\nCHILDREN!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "COMPASSION\nSTRENGTHENS THE\nSOUL AS\nKNOWLEDGE\nTEMPERS THE\nMIND!", 
        "name": "SHALIMAR", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAVE ANY KIDS?", 
        "question_no_answer": "TOO BAD.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THOU DOST KNOW\nWHAT I MEAN!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "AN INJURED\nPERSON.", 
        "health": "NOT SO WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I KNOW A\nTERRIBLE SECRET!", 
        "keyword_1": "SECRET", 
        "keyword_2": "MOND", 
        "keyword_response_1": "MONDAIN'S\nINFLUENCE HAS\nNOT LEFT THE\nWORLD!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "AN ARTIFACT\nREMAINS! I HEARD\nAT BUCCANEER'S\nDEN!", 
        "name": "SEBASTIAN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU FIND\nAND DESTROY IT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "OH.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN ASK AT THE\nPUB THERE OF\nTHE SKULL!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A DRUID.", 
        "health": "ALL RIGHT.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM LOOKING\nFOR JULIO.", 
        "keyword_1": "JULIO", 
        "keyword_2": "COMP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "HE KNOWS THE\nTRUE NATURE OF\nCOMPASSION.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SEEK OUT JULIO\nAND ASK HIM OF\nCOMPASSION!", 
        "name": "SHAPERO", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU ON THE\nQUEST OF THE\nAVATAR?", 
        "question_no_answer": "TOO BAD.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "FIND THE SHRINE\nOF COMPASSION\nEAST ACROSS 2\nBRIDGES!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SOLEMN BARD.", 
        "health": "SOLEMN.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I SEEK THE\nTRUE NATURE\nOF THINGS!", 
        "keyword_1": "NATURE", 
        "keyword_2": "COMP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "ALL THINGS HAVE\nA TRUE NATURE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "COMPASSION\nDERIVES ITSELF\nFROM UNENDING\nLOVE!", 
        "name": "JULIO", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU KNOW\nTHE TRUE NATURE\nOF ALL THINGS?", 
        "question_no_answer": "NO MORTAL CAN.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THOU ART A LIAR\nAND A BRAGGART.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WISE SHEPHERD.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I ESCAPED\nMAGINCIA!", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGIN", 
        "keyword_2": "PRIDE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "PRIDE WAS TOO\nGREAT IN\nMAGINCIA!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE CITY WAS\nDESTROYED BY\nDAEMONS FOR\nITS PRIDE!", 
        "name": "MENTOR", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU PROUD?", 
        "question_no_answer": "PRIDE EXISTS\nWITHOUT TRUTH,\nLOVE, OR\nCOURAGE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THAT IS NOT\nA VIRTUE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A POOR BEGGAR.", 
        "health": "I FEAR I\nSHALL DIE OF\nSTARVATION!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I HAVE NO JOB SO\nNOW I BEG!", 
        "keyword_1": "STARV", 
        "keyword_2": "BEG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I HAVE NOT EATEN\nIN A WEEK!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "PLEASE! HELP ME!", 
        "name": "SPRITE", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU\nHELP ME?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I SHALL STARVE\nTO DEATH!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "IN RETURN I\nSHALL TELL THEE\nTHAT PEPPER\nKNOWS OF THE\nRUNE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A 6 FOOT 5,\nGREAT WARRIOR.", 
        "health": "I AM GOOD\nAND STRONG!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I LEAD INTO\nBATTLE!", 
        "keyword_1": "WARR", 
        "keyword_2": "BATT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A GREAT WARRIOR\nIS A VALIANT\nWARRIOR!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I DESIRE TO\nFIGHT AGAIN IN\nBATTLE!", 
        "name": "GEOFFREY", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU\nVALIANT!", 
        "question_no_answer": "TO FLEE BATTLE\nSHOWS COWARDICE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "PERHAPS I COULD\nSOMEDAY JOIN\nTHEE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A MYSTERIOUS\nWARRIOR.", 
        "health": "OUTSTANDING!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I BATTLE FOR\nLORD BRITISH!", 
        "keyword_1": "WARR", 
        "keyword_2": "BATT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THOU MUST BATTLE\nLONG AND HARD\nTO BE A WARRIOR.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "BATTLES ARE FEW\nAND TOO MANY!", 
        "name": "LORD ROBERT", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ARE YOU A\nVALIANT WARRIOR?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THOU ART A WIMP!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THOU DOST\nDESERVE THE\nRUNE, ASK\nNOSTRO!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A 5 FOOT\nPREGNANT WOMAN.", 
        "health": "FINE, ALL BUT\nTHE LUMP IN\nMY STOMACH.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I WATCH OVER\nMY SHEEP.", 
        "keyword_1": "PREG", 
        "keyword_2": "SHEEP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "IT'S NO FUN\nTO BE PREGNANT.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I CAN'T STAND\nSHEEP!", 
        "name": "LADY DONNA", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "WHY, ART THOU\nTHE FATHER?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THANK GOD!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WAIT TILL I\nTELL MY HUSBAND!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WOUNDED\nFIGHTER!", 
        "health": "POOR.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEARCH THE\nDUNGEONS!", 
        "keyword_1": "DUNG", 
        "keyword_2": "ROOM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I FELL IN\nTHE DUNGEON\n'DESTARD'.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THEREIN USE THE\nSTONES FOUND IN\nTHE CONNECTING\nDUNGEONS!", 
        "name": "BENGROD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU FOUND\nITS ALTAR ROOM?", 
        "question_no_answer": "FIND IT!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "IT CONNECTS WITH\nCOVETOUS, SHAME\nAND HYTHLOTH!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A NOBLE FIGHTER.", 
        "health": "VERY WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEARCH\nFOR VALIANT\nFIGHTERS!", 
        "keyword_1": "EVIL", 
        "keyword_2": "KILL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "KILL NOT\nNON-EVIL\nCREATURES BUT\nSTILL ALWAYS\nSTAND THY\nGROUND!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "LET THEM FLEE\nINSTEAD. NEVER\nFLEE UNINJURED!", 
        "name": "SIR WILLIAM", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU\nVALIANT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I SEE.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "STRIVE YE TO\nDEFEAT ALL EVIL!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A MIGHTY\nWARRIOR!", 
        "health": "EXCELLENT.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I FIGHT FOR\nVALOR!", 
        "keyword_1": "VALOR", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE VALIANT SOUL\nFEARS NOT ITS\nOWN VISAGE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE MANTRA NEED\nBE KNOWN, ASK\nAESOP!", 
        "name": "SIR HROTHGAR", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU THE\nMOST VALIANT OF\nSOULS?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THOU SHOULD SEEK\nTHE SHRINE OF\nVALOR!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THIS IS NOT\nLIKELY!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A STERN GUARD.", 
        "health": "WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "WE GUARD THE\nGATES AND THESE\nPASSAGES!", 
        "keyword_1": "GATES", 
        "keyword_2": "PASSAG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE GATES\nOF JHELOM.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THESE PASSAGES\nARE RESTRICTED.", 
        "name": "A GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SMALL MAN.", 
        "health": "WELL ENOUGH.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEARCH\nFOR VALOR!", 
        "keyword_1": "VALOR", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I FIND THAT 'TIS\nEASY TO BE BRAVE\nFROM A SAFE\nDISTANCE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE MANTRA OF\nVALOR IS 'RA'.\nUSE IT IN THE\nSHRINE ON THE\nNEXT ISLE!", 
        "name": "AESOP", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "KNOW WHAT\nI MEAN?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THOU ART BRAVE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THATS MY\nPROBLEM.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A GRAVE FIGHTER.", 
        "health": "SO SO.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEARCH THE\nDUNGEONS.", 
        "keyword_1": "DUNG", 
        "keyword_2": "STON", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I SEEK THE\nRED STONE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "IT IS FOUND ON\nAN ALTAR!", 
        "name": "GRAVNOR", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nHAVE IT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "IT LIES IN THE\nDUNGEON DESTARD!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "NO WONDER I\nCAN'T FIND IT!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BEAUTIFUL\nMAGE.", 
        "health": "WELL ENOUGH.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM LOCKED UP\nIN THIS TOWER.", 
        "keyword_1": "TOWER", 
        "keyword_2": "CRIMES", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I AM BEING\nPUNISHED FOR MY\nCRIMES.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "DOES NOT MATTER,\nI CAN HELP THEE!", 
        "name": "SENORA", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU HAVE\nA SHIP?", 
        "question_no_answer": "TOO BAD.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN THOU DOST\nNEED A SEXTANT.\nASK THE BARKEEP\nFOR HE KNOWS\nMORE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WITHERING\nSOUL.", 
        "health": "VERY NEAR DEATH!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I BUILT THESE\nPASSAGES AND\nTHEY WALLED\nME IN!", 
        "keyword_1": "PASSAG", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THIS PASSAGE\nRUNS AROUND THE\nCITY!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE RUNE IS\nBURIED IN A\nTOWER!", 
        "name": "NOSTRO", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU LEAD\nME OUT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THOU ART A CAD!\nAND I WILL STILL\nFOLLOW!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I AM SAVED!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A RANGER WITH A\nFAR AWAY LOOK.", 
        "health": "QUITE WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEEK THE\nINNER LIGHT!", 
        "keyword_1": "LIGHT", 
        "keyword_2": "YEW", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I COME FROM\nSKARA BRAE AND\nAM ON MY WAY TO\nYEW.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "'TIS A CITY\nBASED IN THE\nVIRTUE OF\nJUSTICE!", 
        "name": "LUKE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU BEEN\nTO SKARA BRAE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "'TIS A SPIRITUAL\nCITY!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A FINE CITY!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "THE HOUSEKEEPER.", 
        "health": "GOOD!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM THE\nHOUSEKEEPER.", 
        "keyword_1": "HOUSE", 
        "keyword_2": "ROOM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I CLEAN\nTHE ROOMS.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THAT'S A STRANGE\nONE AT THE\nEND. PEOPLE\nOFTEN DISAPPEAR.", 
        "name": "MAX", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "IS THERE SOME\nPROBLEM WITH THY\nROOM?", 
        "question_no_answer": "OH, THOU HAD\nME WORRIED!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I AM VERY SORRY\nI WILL CORRECT\nIT RIGHT AWAY!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A STRANGE\nPERSON.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I SEEK THE STONE", 
        "keyword_1": "STONE", 
        "keyword_2": "RED", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE RED STONE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "RED IS FOR VALOR\nA VIRTUE OF THE\nAVATAR!", 
        "name": "X", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU AN\nAVATAR?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN THOU SHALT\nNEED THE RED\nSTONE IN ONE\nALTAR ROOM TO\nGET THE THIRD\nPART OF A KEY!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WOW!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A VALIANT\nWARRIOR.", 
        "health": "ONLY MINOR\nWOUNDS!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I FIGHT BATTLES!", 
        "keyword_1": "BATTLE", 
        "keyword_2": "VALOR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "TRUE VALOR IS\nSEEN NOT IN THE\nFORCE OF ARMS,\nBUT IN THE FORCE\nOF WILL!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I DISPLAY MY\nVALOR IN BATTLE.", 
        "name": "SLITHE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU\nVALIANT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "COWARD.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN NEVER FLEE\nUNLESS THE NEED\nIS DIRE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A THIN FIGHTER.", 
        "health": "COULDN'T BE\nBETTER!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I FIGHT\nWITH VALOR!", 
        "keyword_1": "VALOR", 
        "keyword_2": "BRAVE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THERE IS NO\nHOLIER SPOT OF\nGROUND THAN\nWHERE DEFEATED\nVALOR LIES.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "BE BRAVE FOR\nTHERE IS MUCH\nTO DARE!", 
        "name": "TIMROD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU BRAVE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "COWARD.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "FORTUNE HELPS\nTHE BRAVE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A QUIET DRUID.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I STRIVE TO\nUNDERSTAND\nJUSTICE.", 
        "keyword_1": "JUST", 
        "keyword_2": "UNDER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "TRUE JUSTICE\nSATISFIES ALL,\nFALSE NONE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "LET JUSTICE BE\nTHY CALLING NOT\nTHY EXCUSE!", 
        "name": "JAANA", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "ART THOU JUST?", 
        "question_no_answer": "ALAS.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "MANY A GRAVE HAS\nBEEN UNJUSTLY\nFILLED IN THE\nNAME OF JUSTICE.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL GUARD.", 
        "health": "YES.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "TO GUARD\nTHE COURT.", 
        "keyword_1": "JUST", 
        "keyword_2": "COURT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A GOOD LIFE IS\nINSPIRED BY LOVE\nAND GUIDED BY\nKNOWLEDGE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "WITHIN THIS\nCHAMBER JUSTICE\nIS SERVED.", 
        "name": "A GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU HAVE\nBUSINESS BEFORE\nTHE COURT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN DO NOT\nDISTURB THE\nPROCEEDINGS!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN ENTER.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BIG GUARD.", 
        "health": "FIT.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "WE GUARD\nTHE JAIL.", 
        "keyword_1": "MISD", 
        "keyword_2": "FELON", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THAT'LL BE THE\nLEFT CELL.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THAT'LL BE THE\nRIGHT HAND CELL.\nCAREFUL IN\nTHERE!", 
        "name": "A GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU COME\nTO TURN THYSELF\nIN?", 
        "question_no_answer": "JUST VISITING,\nEH.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "IN WHICH CELL\nDOST THOU\nBELONG, FELONIES\nOR MISDEMEANORS.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SOLEMN DRUID.", 
        "health": "WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I MAKE SPELLS.", 
        "keyword_1": "SPELLS", 
        "keyword_2": "MANDRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I INVENTED\nQUICKNESS!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "MANDRAKE ROOT IS\nFOUND ONLY IN\nTHE FENS OF THE\nDEAD AND IN THE\nBLOODY PLAINS\nWHERE THE GROUND\nIS ALWAYS DAMP.", 
        "name": "CALUMNY", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "CAN THOU\nCAST IT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "ADEPT.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "IT REQUIRES BUT\nONE BLOODMOSS!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WISE JUDGE.", 
        "health": "WELL.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I DECIDE\nJUSTICE.", 
        "keyword_1": "JUST", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "JUSTICE IS TRUTH\nIN ACTION!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "IT IS\nHIDDEN WELL!", 
        "name": "TALFOURD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "CAN THOU\nHONESTLY CLAIM\nTO BE GUILTY OF\nNO CRIME EVER?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN DO THY\nPENANCE IN A\nCELL, AND WITH\nTHE FELON\nSEARCH YE WELL.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "DOUBTFUL.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BURNING FIRE.", 
        "health": "BRIGHT.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I HOLD THE\nFABRIC OF THE\nTRUE NATURE OF\nJUSTICE.", 
        "keyword_1": "JUST", 
        "keyword_2": "FABR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE VIRTUE OF\nJUSTICE DRAWS\nITS NATURE FROM\nTHE PRINCIPLES\nOF TRUTH AND\nLOVE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "OF JUSTICE.", 
        "name": "FLAMIS", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "HAST THOU ALWAYS\nBEEN JUST?", 
        "question_no_answer": "AT LEAST THOU\nART HONEST.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "UNLIKELY.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A CHANTING\nDRUID.", 
        "health": "BEH... BEH...", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "BEH... BEH...", 
        "keyword_1": "BEH...", 
        "keyword_2": "BEH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "BEH... BEH...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "BEH... BEH...", 
        "name": "SILENT", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WISE DRUID.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "WELCOME THEE TO\nYEW, CITY OF\nJUSTICE!", 
        "keyword_1": "JUST", 
        "keyword_2": "YEW", 
        "keyword_response_1": "LOVE NO ONE MORE\nTHAN THE TRUTH,\nFOR JUSTICE\nSEEKS NO FAVORS.\nTEMPER THY\nJUSTICE WITH\nUNDERSTANDING.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "YES 'TIS A\nFAIR CITY!", 
        "name": "DWP", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nLIKE IT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A PITY.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "LET IT BE\nAS THINE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A POOR BEGGAR.", 
        "health": "WELL TREATED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I HAVE SINNED.", 
        "keyword_1": "SINNED", 
        "keyword_2": "FELON", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I HAVE GOTTEN\nCHESTS IN THE\nTOWNES AND\nKILLED NON-EVIL\nCREATURES.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "HE IS A MEAN\nNASTY UGLY\nVILLAIN!", 
        "name": "A POOR BEGGAR", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "SHOULD THOU BE\nIN WITH THE\nFELON?", 
        "question_no_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THOU ART IN THE\nWRONG CELL.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A MEAN NASTY\nUGLY VILLAIN!", 
        "health": "HUNGRY!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I EAT PEOPLE\nWHO BUG ME!", 
        "keyword_1": "VILL", 
        "keyword_2": "PEOPLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THAT'S ME\nALRIGHT!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "LIKE THEE!", 
        "name": "VORPAL", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU HERE\nTO BUG ME?", 
        "question_no_answer": "WELL THOU ART!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "EAT DEATH,\nSCUM PUPPY!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 60
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SLEEK RANGER.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEARCH FOR\nA HOME.", 
        "keyword_1": "HOME", 
        "keyword_2": "RANGE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "ON THE RANGE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "WHERE THE DEER\nAND THE ANTELOPE\nPLAY.", 
        "name": "A RANGER", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "EVER HEARD OF\nSUCH A PLACE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "AH, WHAT'YA HAVE\nTO RUIN IT FOR!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "SELDOM IS HEARD\nA DISCOURAGING\nWORD!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SMALL CHILD.", 
        "health": "I AM FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I WORK FOR\nJONES.", 
        "keyword_1": "JONES", 
        "keyword_2": "QUEST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I THINK INDI'S\nON A QUEST!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I'M NOT SO SURE,\nBUT IT SHOULD BE\nFUN!", 
        "name": "SHORT ROUND", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU\nHAVING FUN?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I AM SO SORRY WE\nALL WISH YOU\nWOULD!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WRITE TO LORD\nBRITISH AND TELL\nHIM!!!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WITHERED FORM.", 
        "health": "I AM STARVING\nAND SICK.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "SEE MY POOR\nBABY? I BEG\nFOR HIM.", 
        "keyword_1": "BABY", 
        "keyword_2": "JUST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "OH, NO, MY BABY\nIS DYING!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "JAANA MAY\nJOIN THEE!", 
        "name": "FRIDA", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU GIVE\nME MONEY SO THAT\nI CAN GET MY\nBABY HEALED?", 
        "question_no_answer": "EVIL WRETCH,\nCURSE THEE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THOU ART KIND\nAND JUST!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A THIN MAN.", 
        "health": "FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I TAKE COUNCIL.", 
        "keyword_1": "COUN", 
        "keyword_2": "JUST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "ON JUSTICE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "JUSTICE IS\nHARDEST TO FIND\nAT THE POINT OF\nA SWORD, THE\nSTEEL IS AN\nAGENT OF\nJUSTICE,\nHUMANITY THE\nPERPETRATOR!", 
        "name": "PINROD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "FIGHT YE FOR\nJUSTICE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "CAD.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD, THE\nDRUIDS CHANT\nTHE MANTRA!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BIG GUARD.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "TO PRESERVE\nTHE PEACE AND\nINSURE JUSTICE!", 
        "keyword_1": "PEACE", 
        "keyword_2": "JUST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A GOOD LIFE IS\nINSPIRED BY LOVE\nAND GUIDED BY\nTRUTH!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "JUSTICE MEANS\nNOT ONLY TO\nPUNISH THE BAD\nBUT ALSO TO\nREWARD THE GOOD!", 
        "name": "A GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU\nALWAYS JUST?", 
        "question_no_answer": "STRIVE TO BE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "UNLIKELY!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WANDERING\nDRUID.", 
        "health": "WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEEK JUSTICE.", 
        "keyword_1": "JUST", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRI", 
        "keyword_response_1": "LEARN AT\nTHE SHRINE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE SHRINE IS TO\nTHE EAST THEN\nNORTH!", 
        "name": "DRUID", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU HAVE\nTHE RUNE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "ASK TALFOURD FOR\nHE KNOWS OF THE\nRUNE.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "NOW LEARN THE\nMANTRA, AND SEEK\nTHE GREEN STONE\nIN 'WRONG'!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "AN AGILE TINKER.", 
        "health": "WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I CARE FOR\nTHE POOR.", 
        "keyword_1": "CARE", 
        "keyword_2": "POOR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "SELF\nPRESERVATION IS\nTHE FIRST LAW OF\nNATURE; SELF\nSACRIFICE THE\nHIGHEST RULE\nOF GRACE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "WITHIN THIS\nHOUSE ARE MANY\nPOOR AND\nDESTITUTE SOULS.", 
        "name": "JULIA", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU HELP?", 
        "question_no_answer": "BUM.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I WOULD\nJOIN THEE.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SEASONED\nBLACKSMITH.", 
        "health": "QUITE WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I FORGE WEAPONS.", 
        "keyword_1": "WEAP", 
        "keyword_2": "MYSTIC", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I MAKE THE\nVERY BEST!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "AH, YES, THE\nMYSTIC WEAPONS,\nAND ARMOUR, MY\nGREATEST WORK!\nTHOSE I GAVE\nUNTO SIR SIMON\nAND LADY TESSA.", 
        "name": "ZIRCON", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "SEEK THEE\nA WEAPON?", 
        "question_no_answer": "HMMM.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "ASK AT THE\nCOUNTER!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SICKLY\nLITTLE MAN.", 
        "health": "I AM VERY SICK,\nHELP ME!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I HAVE NONE,\nHELP ME.", 
        "keyword_1": "HELP", 
        "keyword_2": "SICK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I NEED MONEY\nTO CURE MY\nSICKNESS.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I HAVE TERMINAL\nLEG ROT.", 
        "name": "BOB THE BEGGAR", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU\nANY MONEY?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN JOIN ME AND\nWE CAN BEG\nTOGETHER!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN PLEASE\nSHARE IT\nWITH ME!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SMALL\nMUDDY GIRL.", 
        "health": "I AM HUNGRY.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I'M AN\nUNDERNOURISHED\nBEGGAR GIRL.", 
        "keyword_1": "HUNG", 
        "keyword_2": "FOOD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I HAVE NOT EATEN\nIN DAYS.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "OH, THOU ART\nA KIND SOUL!", 
        "name": "LINDA SUE", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "COULD THOU SPARE\nA NIBBLE OF\nFOOD?", 
        "question_no_answer": "OH, I SEE.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I WOULD GREATLY\nAPPRECIATE THAT.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A FADING MAN.", 
        "health": "I AM BARELY\nCONSCIOUS.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SHALL\nDIE SOON.", 
        "keyword_1": "DIE", 
        "keyword_2": "CONSC", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I SUFFER FROM A\nTSETSE BYTE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I WILL SOON\nSLEEP FOREVER.", 
        "name": "GIMBLE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "COULD THOU SPARE\nA GOLD PIECE SO\nI MAY BUY A\nLAST DRINK?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I AM SADDENED.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "REMEMBER AZURE\nKNOWS OF THE\nRUNE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 40
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A RAGGED SOUL.", 
        "health": "AILING.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "TO REDEEM\nMYSELF!", 
        "keyword_1": "REDEEM", 
        "keyword_2": "SKULL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I WILL NOT SPEAK\nOF MY SIN!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I USED IT!", 
        "name": "JUDE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "IF I HELP THEE,\nWILT THOU SWEAR\nTO ONLY USE IT\nAT THE MOUTH OF\nTHE ABYSS TO\nDESTROY IT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "OH.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "IT CAN BE FOUND\nAT LAT-P'F\"\nLONG-M'F\" ON THE\nDARKEST NIGHT!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "AN OLD\nRAGGED MAN.", 
        "health": "I AM OLD\nAND WEAK.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM A PEASANT,\nI HEAR MANY\nTHINGS.", 
        "keyword_1": "HEAR", 
        "keyword_2": "STONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WHAT DOES THOU\nWISH TO KNOW?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE STONE OF\nSACRIFICE IS\nORANGE IN COLOR\nAND USED IN THE\nALTAR ROOMS OF\nLOVE AND\nCOURAGE!", 
        "name": "ALKERION", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "SEEKETH THOU?", 
        "question_no_answer": "OH.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD LUCK.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A STOCKY RANGER.", 
        "health": "WELL ENOUGH.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM TRYING TO\nGET A ROOM.", 
        "keyword_1": "ROOM", 
        "keyword_2": "SKARA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I HAVE TRAVELLED\nCLEAR FROM\nSKARA BRAE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE RUNE OF OUR\nCITY IS MISSING!", 
        "name": "MIKE WARD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "KNOW THEE\nOF THE RUNE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "IT IS NOT IN\nSKARA BRAE.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "IT IS THE KEY TO\nTHE SHRINE OF\nSPIRITUALITY!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TEENAGE BOY.", 
        "health": "FINE, THANKS.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I GIVE OUT\nFLOWERS. HERE\nYOU ARE!", 
        "keyword_1": "FLOWER", 
        "keyword_2": "KIND", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE WAY I FIGURE\nIT, IF THOU ART\nKIND TO OTHERS\nTHEY WILL HAVE\nREASON TO BE\nKIND IN RETURN!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "YES, GIVE ALL\nTHAT THOU CAN\nUNTO THE NEEDY!", 
        "name": "ALEX", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU GIVE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "ALAS.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A ROTUND TINKER.", 
        "health": "OK.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I WELCOME THEE\nUNTO MINOC, CITY\nOF SACRIFICE!", 
        "keyword_1": "SACR", 
        "keyword_2": "VIRTUE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "SELF-SACRIFICE\nIS A NEEDED\nVIRTUE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "AVATARS STRIVE\nTO BE VIRTUOUS.", 
        "name": "SHENTIS", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU STRIVE\nFOR VIRTUE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "AN AVATAR THOU\nART NOT!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN PERHAPS\nTHOU SHALT\nBECOME AN\nAVATAR!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A CUTE BARD.", 
        "health": "VERY WELL\nINDEED!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SING SONGS!", 
        "keyword_1": "SING", 
        "keyword_2": "SONG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I SING SONGS!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "VERY WELL,\nTHE RAVEN SINGS,\nTHE RAVEN SAW\nAND IN THE CORN\nHE SAYETH 'CAH'.", 
        "name": "SINGSONG", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nLIKE IT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "TOO BAD...", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THANKS.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A MEEK SHEPHERD.", 
        "health": "FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I STAND HERE\nAND THINK.", 
        "keyword_1": "THINK", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "OH, JUST\nABOUT THINGS.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "LISTEN TO THE\nBARD'S SONG FOR\nIN ITS VERSE\nLIES THE KEY!", 
        "name": "DAMON", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "CAN'T A MAN\nJUST THINK\nTO HIMSELF?", 
        "question_no_answer": "OH, YES\nI CAN THOU\nBANDERSNATCH!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WELL I HOPE SO!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 10
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A HAPPY TINKER.", 
        "health": "O.K. I GUESS.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "THIS AND THAT.", 
        "keyword_1": "THIS", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "AND THAT...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE RUNE OF\nSACRIFICE IS\nHARD TO GET. IT\nLIES WITHIN THE\nFIRES OF THE\nFORGE!", 
        "name": "MISCHIEF", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU\nTHE RUNE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "RETURN WHEN THOU\nDOST FIND IT!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN ASK\nALKERION OF THE\nSTONE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TINKER AT\nTHE TABLE.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I CARVE RUNES.", 
        "keyword_1": "RUNES", 
        "keyword_2": "SACRI", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I CARVE RUNES\nFOR PASSAGE INTO\nTHE SHRINES!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "ASK MY SISTER,\nMISCHIEF.", 
        "name": "AZURE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nSEEK A RUNE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I SEE.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHICH?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WANDERING\nTINKER.", 
        "health": "BEEN BETTER.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEEK THE\nWISDOM OF THE\nSHRINE OF\nSACRIFICE.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "BUT FIRST I NEED\nTHE MANTRA!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I AM TOLD THAT A\nHIDDEN SHEPHERD\nKNOWS THE\nMANTRA.", 
        "name": "MERIDA", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "KNOW YE\nTHE MANTRA?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THE SHRINE IS ON\nA LAKE TO THE\nEAST!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A MASSIVE GUARD.", 
        "health": "QUITE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "TO GUARD\nOF COURSE.", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "LIFE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I OFTEN WONDER\nIF I WILL EVER\nHAVE TO GIVE MY\nLIFE IN THE LINE\nOF DUTY.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "ONE LIFE\nFOR MANY!", 
        "name": "A GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "UNDERSTAND\nMY DILEMMA?", 
        "question_no_answer": "TOO BAD.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "OF COURSE, IF IT\nCAME DOWN TO IT,\nI HOPE I WOULD\nDO IT!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A HANDSOME\nFIGHTER.", 
        "health": "VERY WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM TOWNE\nLEADER", 
        "keyword_1": "LEAD", 
        "keyword_2": "HONOR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "'TIS AN HONOR!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "IT GIVES\nLIFE MEANING!", 
        "name": "DUPRE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU TRY TO\nLIVE HONORABLY?", 
        "question_no_answer": "FOOL!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "IT IS A CONSTANT\nQUEST. HONOR IS\nLIKE FINELY\nPOLISHED ARMOUR.\nWITHOUT CONSTANT\nCARE, IT WILL\nSOON TARNISH!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A MYSTIC WIZARD.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I CREATE MAGICAL\nFIELDS.", 
        "keyword_1": "FIELDS", 
        "keyword_2": "NIGHT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "POISON IS MY\nFAVORITE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "NIGHTSHADE MAY\nBE FOUND ONLY\nNEAR LAT-J'F\"\nLONG-C'O\" ONLY\nON THE DARKEST\nOF NIGHTS!", 
        "name": "VIRGIL", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "IS IT THINE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "WELL I\nDON'T CARE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "BRAVO!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SLEEPY\nFIGHTER.", 
        "health": "TIRED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I DRINK A TOAST\nTO HONOR!", 
        "keyword_1": "HONOR", 
        "keyword_2": "NOTHIN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WHAT IS LEFT\nWHEN HONOR IS\nLOST?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "RIGHT, TAKE\nHONOR FROM ME\nAND MY LIFE IS\nDONE!", 
        "name": "PUBLIUS", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU STRIVE\nTO LIVE AN\nHONORABLE LIFE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "NO HONOR,\nNO MEANING!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "HONOR GIVES\nGREATNESS.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BONY SKELETON.", 
        "health": "WHAT DO\nYOU MEAN?", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I HAIL FROM\nDUNGEON DEEP.", 
        "keyword_1": "DUNG", 
        "keyword_2": "STONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I COME FROM THE\nDUNGEON 'SHAME'!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I HAVE SEEN THE\nPURPLE STONE\nUSED IN THE\nALTARS OF\nTRUTH AND\nCOURAGE!", 
        "name": "SKITLE", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "EVER BEEN THERE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "IT HOLDS ITEMS\nTHOU SHALT NEED.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "AN UGLY SAILOR.", 
        "health": "A BIT\nWATERLOGGED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SAIL THE\nTHE SEAS OF\nBRITANNIA!", 
        "keyword_1": "SEAS", 
        "keyword_2": "SEXT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "MY SPECIALTY IS\nNAVIGATION!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "GO TO THE PUB IN\nJHELOM AND ASK\nOF SEXTANTS.", 
        "name": "SAILOR SAM", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "IS IT THY\nSPECIALTY?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THOU MUST\nNOT OWN A\nSEXTANT, EH?", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD SHOW MATE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A DIGNIFIED\nPALADIN.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I SEARCH\nFOR HONOR.", 
        "keyword_1": "HONOR", 
        "keyword_2": "DIGNIT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "DIGNITY\nCONSISTS NOT\nIN POSSESSING\nHONORS, BUT IN\nDESERVING THEM.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "HONOR NO ONE,\nBUT HONOR\nITSELF!", 
        "name": "ARISTOTLE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU\nHONORABLE AT ALL\nTIMES?", 
        "question_no_answer": "STRIVE TO BE AS\nSUCH.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THAT IS\nIMPRESSIVE.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A COWERING\nCHILD.", 
        "health": "SCARED!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I RAN FROM\nTHE BULL!", 
        "keyword_1": "BULL", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A BIG ONE, WITH\nLONG, POINTY\nHORNS!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "IT IS BURIED IN\nTHE SOUTHWEST\nCORNER OF TOWNE.", 
        "name": "TERRIN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "IS IT GONE YET?", 
        "question_no_answer": "SAVE ME!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHEW, I THOUGHT\nIT WOULD GET ME!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A STRONG\nPALADIN.", 
        "health": "EXTRA GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM\nTHE WELCOMER.", 
        "keyword_1": "WELCOM", 
        "keyword_2": "HONOR", 
        "keyword_response_1": "YES, WELCOME TO\nTRINSIC CITY OF\nHONOR!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "WISDOM ON THE\nVIRTUE OF HONOR\nIS FOUND\nTHROUGHOUT THIS\nTOWNE.", 
        "name": "RIGMORE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU SEEK\nTHIS WISDOM?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THIS IS THE\nWRONG PLACE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "ENTER AND FIND\nTHY PATH.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SCRUFFY\nMERCHANT.", 
        "health": "A BIT\nRAGGED OUT.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I TRADE\nIN RUMORS.", 
        "keyword_1": "RUMOR", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "ABOUT WHAT?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THERE IS A SMALL\nCHILD WHO KNEW\nNAMED... TERRIN.", 
        "name": "WINTHROP", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nKNOW HIM?", 
        "question_no_answer": "FIND HIM AND ASK\nOF THE RUNE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "ASK HIM OF\nTHE RUNE.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL WIZARD.", 
        "health": "FULLY HEALED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I CAST SPELLS.", 
        "keyword_1": "SPELLS", 
        "keyword_2": "MANDRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "SPELLS OF\nGREAT POWER.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "ASK AT THE\nFOLLEY TAVERN\nOF MANDRAKE.", 
        "name": "SWINDRIK", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU CAST\nSPELLS OF GREAT\nPOWER?", 
        "question_no_answer": "DOST THOU KNOW\nTHEIR MAIN\nINGREDIENT?", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHAT IS THE\nMOST POWERFUL\nREAGENT?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SEARCHING\nPALADIN!", 
        "health": "WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEEK ENTRY TO\nTHE SHRINE OF\nHONOR!", 
        "keyword_1": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE MANTRA\nIS 'SUMM'.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A MAN NAMED\nWINTHROP KNOWS\nOF THE RUNE!", 
        "name": "KLINE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "KNOW YE THE TWO\nREQUIREMENTS TO\nENTER AND USE\nTHE SHRINE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "WHAT DOST\nTHOU THINK?", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHAT ARE THEY?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SHINING\nPALADIN.", 
        "health": "SUPERB.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM WARLORD\nOF TRINSIC.", 
        "keyword_1": "WARLOR", 
        "keyword_2": "QUESTS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I HAVE SOLVED\nMANY QUESTS!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE SOLVING OF\nQUESTS BRINGS YE\nHONOR!", 
        "name": "LEXINGTON", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "STRIVE YE\nFOR HONOR?", 
        "question_no_answer": "OH.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN SOLVE\nQUESTS BUT\nATTACK NOT\nNON-EVIL\nCREATURES, AND\nGET NOT\nOTHERS GOLD!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SOULFUL\nFIGHTER.", 
        "health": "TIRED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEEK A PLACE\nTO REST.", 
        "keyword_1": "REST", 
        "keyword_2": "QUEST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I HAVE QUESTED\nLONG AND HARD.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I SEEK\nENLIGHTENMENT\nAT THE SHRINE OF\nHONOR!", 
        "name": "DERGIN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU\nENLIGHTENED\nIN HONOR?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THE SHRINE LIES\nTO THE SOUTH AND\nWEST BEYOND THE\nSWAMPS!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BIG GUARD.", 
        "health": "EXCELLENT.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "WE GUARD\nTHE GATE.", 
        "keyword_1": "GATE", 
        "keyword_2": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "INTO AND OUT\nOF TRINSIC.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "'TIS AN\nHONORABLE JOB!", 
        "name": "A GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU STRIVE\nTO BRING HONOR\nUPON THE PEERS?", 
        "question_no_answer": "DOLT.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "DUPRE, THE\nLEADER OF OUR\nTOWNE, JOINS\nMANY HONORABLE\nQUESTS!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WANDERING\nMAGE.", 
        "health": "ADEQUATE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEEK THE\nSKELETON!", 
        "keyword_1": "SKEL", 
        "keyword_2": "SECRET", 
        "keyword_response_1": "IT KNOWS A\nGREAT SECRET.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "ABOUT THE PURPLE\nSTONE OF HONOR!", 
        "name": "QUIX", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU HAVE\nTHE PURPLE\nSTONE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "SEEK IT FOR IT\nIS VERY USEFUL!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "USE IT WISELY!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A STRONG GUARD.", 
        "health": "GUARDED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "TO GUARD.", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "STRONG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "GUARDING.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "GUARD", 
        "name": "A GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 40
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SOLEMN RANGER.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEEK THE\nINNER LIGHT.", 
        "keyword_1": "LIGHT", 
        "keyword_2": "TRUTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I SEEK THE \"ONE\nGREAT TRUTH\"!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THAT WHICH\nLIES WITHIN\nTHE CODEX!", 
        "name": "SHAMINO", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU SEEK\nTHIS \"TRUTH\"?", 
        "question_no_answer": "ALAS.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "SOME THINGS TAKE\nFOREVER BUT\nBRICK BY BRICK\nMOUNTAINS CAN BE\nBUILT!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "AN INJURED MAN.", 
        "health": "I AM GRIEVOUSLY\nWOUNDED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEEK THE\nSPIRITUAL PATH.", 
        "keyword_1": "SPIRIT", 
        "keyword_2": "WOUND", 
        "keyword_response_1": "SPIRITUAL IS\nSTRONGER THAN\nANY MATERIAL\nFORCE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "NOTHING CAN\nBRING THEE PEACE\nBUT THE TRIUMPH\nOF PRINCIPLES!", 
        "name": "EMERSON", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU GOOD\nIN SPIRIT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "AN EVIL PATH!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A GOOD PATH.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL RANGER.", 
        "health": "I AM ALIVE.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I CARRY THE\nLIGHT WITHIN MY\nHEART.", 
        "keyword_1": "LIGHT", 
        "keyword_2": "PHILOS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE LIGHT OF\nPHILOSOPHY.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "IN PHILOSOPHICAL\nMINDS THE\nFAMILIAR EXCITES\nWONDER!", 
        "name": "SANTAYANA", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU ALWAYS\nTREAD THE RIGHT\nPATH?", 
        "question_no_answer": "FEW CAN, BUT\nSTRIVE TO DO SO!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "DOUBTFUL!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A VERY SMALL\nWIZARD.", 
        "health": "SUPERIOR!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I CAST GREAT\nBIG SPELLS!", 
        "keyword_1": "SPELLS", 
        "keyword_2": "NIGHT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I CAN CAST:\nJINX, KILL,\nAND VIEW!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "YES, ASK THE\nBARKEEP AT\n'THE AXE-N-ALE'\nIN VESPER ABOUT\nNIGHTSHADE.", 
        "name": "PRESTO", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU KNOW\nWHAT THESE\nSPELLS HAVE IN\nCOMMON?", 
        "question_no_answer": "GUESS!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHAT?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A HUNGRY BEGGAR.", 
        "health": "I AM NOT\nAT ALL WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I BEG FOR FOOD\nAND MONEY.", 
        "keyword_1": "FOOD", 
        "keyword_2": "MONEY", 
        "keyword_response_1": "TO EAT!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "TO BUY FOOD!", 
        "name": "GRANTED", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU GIVE\nME FOOD OR\nMONEY?", 
        "question_no_answer": "JERK!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "IN RETURN I WILL\nTELL THEE THAT\nTHE ANKH KNOWS\nOF THE RUNE AND\nMY FRIEND AMBULE\nKNOWS THE\nMANTRA!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A RADIANT\nRANGER.", 
        "health": "I AM FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM READING THE\nWIZARD'S\nJOURNAL.", 
        "keyword_1": "JOURN", 
        "keyword_2": "STONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "IT TELLS OF THE\nWHITE STONE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "IT IS NO LONGER\nIN THE DUNGEON\nHYTHLOTH, IT\nIS GONE!", 
        "name": "MITRE", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU TRY TO\nRECOVER IT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "TOO BAD.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "ASK OF THE STONE\nAT THE TAP IN\nTRINSIC!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A GREAT\nPHILOSOPHER.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I TEACH.", 
        "keyword_1": "TEACH", 
        "keyword_2": "NOBLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WHEN ONE HAS\nPITY ON ALL\nLIVING CREATURES\nTHEN IS ONE\nNOBLE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "IF ONE SPEAKS OR\nACTS WITH PURE\nTHOUGHT,\nHAPPINESS WILL\nFOLLOW LIKE A\nSHADOW THAT\nNEVER LEAVES.", 
        "name": "BUDDHA", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SKILLED\nRANGER.", 
        "health": "WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I STRIVE ALONG\nTHE PATH.", 
        "keyword_1": "PATH", 
        "keyword_2": "JOURN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "SUCCESS IS A\nJOURNEY, NOT A\nDESTINATION.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "MAY THOU ALWAYS\nDESIRE MORE THAN\nTHOU CAN\nACCOMPLISH!", 
        "name": "MICHAELANGELO", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU FAR\nALONG THE PATH?", 
        "question_no_answer": "FEAR NOT THOU\nSHALT BE.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THIS IS GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SHORT DUMPY\nMAN WITH A BOOK.", 
        "health": "I AM FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM A TEACHER,\nI ENRICH YOUNG\nMINDS.", 
        "keyword_1": "TEACH", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I TEACH OF\nTHE ABYSS.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SEEK ZAIR THE\nWISE IN PAWS FOR\nMORE ON THE\nWORD.", 
        "name": "ROMASCO", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "KNOW YE OF\nTHE ABYSS?", 
        "question_no_answer": "LEARN!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A WORD OF\nPASSAGE IS\nNEEDED AT THE\nLAST GATE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WISE MAGE.", 
        "health": "FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I WRITE MAGIC.", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGIC", 
        "keyword_2": "BELIE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "ONE LIVES BY\nBELIEVING IN\nSOMETHING.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "GREAT\nDISCOVERIES ARE\nMADE BY THOSE\nWHOSE FEELINGS\nRUN AHEAD OF\nTHEIR THINKING.", 
        "name": "CARLYLE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nBELIEVE IN\nMAGIC?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I SEE.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "MAGIC MISSILES\nNEED BUT 1\nPART ASH!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WISE BARD.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I WRITE STORIES.", 
        "keyword_1": "STOR", 
        "keyword_2": "SPIRIT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "STORIES ARE GOOD\nFOR THE SPIRIT!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "REMEMBER,\nNO ONE IS\nUSELESS IN THIS\nWORLD WHO\nLIGHTENS THE\nBURDENS OF\nOTHERS!", 
        "name": "DICKENS", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU GOOD\nIN NATURE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I SEE.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "BE SURE THY NET\nGOOD WELL\nEXCEEDS THY\nNET EVIL!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A GALLANT\nFIGHTER.", 
        "health": "EXCELLENT!", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I QUEST.", 
        "keyword_1": "QUEST", 
        "keyword_2": "DANGER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "MANY QUESTS ARE\nVERY DANGEROUS!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I AM NOT AFRAID\nOF TOMORROW; I\nHAVE SEEN\nYESTERDAY AND I\nLOVE TODAY.", 
        "name": "WHITE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU\nFEARLESS IN ALL\nTHINGS?", 
        "question_no_answer": "DANGER IS REAL!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "BOASTFUL FOOL!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SILVER ANKH.", 
        "health": "STRONG.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I KEEP THE\nSECRET OF\nTHE RUNE.", 
        "keyword_1": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_2": "OM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "MANTRA?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SEARCH FOR\nTHE RUNE OF\nSPIRITUALITY IN\nTHE TREASURE\nCHAMBER OF\nBRITANNIA!", 
        "name": "THE ANKH OF\nSPIRITUALITY", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "HAST THOU FOUND\nTHE SHRINE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "ENTER THE GATE\nOF FULL MOONS!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A GRIMY BEGGAR.", 
        "health": "SO-SO.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I BEG FOR BUT\nFOR A SINGLE\nGOLD PIECE!", 
        "keyword_1": "BEG", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "OH, PLEASE...\nOH, PLEASE...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "ASK THE CHILD\nNAMED BARREN.", 
        "name": "AMBULE", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU PLEASE\nGIVE ME A\nGOLD PIECE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "STINGY, I KNOW\nTHOU HAST MANY!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "DEAR KIND SOUL.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SMALL CHILD.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "NO JOB.", 
        "keyword_1": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I KNOW IT WELL,\nIT IS 'OM'.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "BARREN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A GHOSTLY\nFIGURE.", 
        "health": "I AM MANY\nYEARS DEAD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I HAUNT\nTHIS INN!", 
        "keyword_1": "HAUNT", 
        "keyword_2": "STONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE QUEST IS\nNOT COMPLETE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE WHITE STONE\nSITS ATOP THE\nSERPENT'S SPINE.\nIT CAN ONLY BE\nREACHED BY ONE\nWHO FLOATS\nWITHIN THE\nCLOUDS.", 
        "name": "ISAAC", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU ON\nTHE QUEST?", 
        "question_no_answer": "ALAS.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "HOPE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SHEPHERD.", 
        "health": "WELL.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "A SURVIVOR.", 
        "keyword_1": "SURV", 
        "keyword_2": "PRIDE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "MAGINCIA WAS\nDESTROYED BY ITS\nPRIDE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "PRIDE FLOURISHES\nIN THE ABSENCE\nOF TRUTH, LOVE\nAND COURAGE.", 
        "name": "KATRINA", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "ART THOU PROUD?", 
        "question_no_answer": "HUMILITY IS THE\nVIRTUE THAT\nMUST OVERCOME\nPRIDE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THY EFFORTS\nARE MEANINGLESS.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SHADOWY GHOST.", 
        "health": "UNDEAD IN SEARCH\nOF PEACE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I HAUNT MAGINCIA", 
        "keyword_1": "PEACE", 
        "keyword_2": "SPIRIT", 
        "keyword_response_1": "PEACE I CAN\nNEVER FIND,\nFOREVER BANISHED\nUNTO THE REALM\nOF EARTHBOUND\nSPIRITS.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "BE NOT PROUD OF\nTHY LITTLE DEEDS\nLEST YE TOO FALL\nFROM THE LIGHT!", 
        "name": "GHOSTLY", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A JABBERING\nSKELETON.", 
        "health": "MOST SUPERB.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM A NOBLEMAN\nOF GREAT BIRTH.", 
        "keyword_1": "NOBLE", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "ME AND MY\nBROTHER ARE THE\nLAST TWO OF THE\nGREAT MERIDID\nFAMILY.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "SKULLFACE", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "THOU HAST HEARD\nOF US OF COURSE,\nYES?", 
        "question_no_answer": "YOU MUST NOT BE\nFROM NEAR THESE\nPARTS!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I THOUGHT SO.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SMALL GHOST.", 
        "health": "FEELING A BIT\nTRANSLUCENT.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "TO HAUNT\nTHIS SHOP.", 
        "keyword_1": "HAUNT", 
        "keyword_2": "PRIDE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A LOT OF\nHAUNTING GOES ON\nROUND HERE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SEEK YE THE\nMANTRA FOR\nHUMILITY, ASK YE\nHEYWOOD!", 
        "name": "CASPERIN", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "KNOW THEE WHY?", 
        "question_no_answer": "PRIDE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "PRIDE IS THE\nSUREST MEASURE\nOF GOALS NEVER\nATTAINED!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL GHOST.", 
        "health": "BEEN BETTER.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "OH, I JUST\nHANG AROUND!", 
        "keyword_1": "HANG", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I WAS HUNG FOR\nMY SIN OF PRIDE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE MANTRA FOR\nPRIDE, BEING\nTHE ANTITHESIS\nOF HUMILITY,\nIS 'MUL'.", 
        "name": "FAULTLESS", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "ART THOU PROUD?", 
        "question_no_answer": "PRIDE IS EVIL'S\nFAVORITE SIN!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A GRAVE SIN!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL GHOST.", 
        "health": "AS WELL AS CAN\nBE EXPECTED.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "HAUNT ETERNALLY.", 
        "keyword_1": "HAUNT", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "PRIDE GOETH\nBEFORE, SHAME\nCOMETH AFTER!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "FAULTLESS KNOWS\nTHE MANTRA OF\nPRIDE ASK HIM!", 
        "name": "HEYWOOD", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "ART THOU PROUD?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A PROUD SOUL\nSURELY KNOWS NOT\nITS WORTH!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THOU SHALT\nFIND SHAME!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SKINNY\nSKELETON.", 
        "health": "A BIT ON THE\nTHIN SIDE.", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I RATTLE\nMY BONES.", 
        "keyword_1": "BONES", 
        "keyword_2": "PRIDE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I DID VALUE\nMYSELF FAR TOO\nGREATLY, THAT\nPRIDE WAS MY\nDOWNFALL.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A TERRIBLE\nTHING!", 
        "name": "SLIM", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "ART THOU\nALWAYS HUMBLE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "TAKE NO PRIDE IN\nHUMILITY, LEST\nYE DESTROY IT!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "DOUBTFUL.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A CRUMBLING\nSKELETON.", 
        "health": "A BIT BONY.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I ONCE HELD THE\nSILVER HORN.", 
        "keyword_1": "HORN", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE SILVER HORN\nMUST BE USED TO\nPASS THE DAEMON\nGUARD OF THE\nSHRINE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "WIERDRUM HAS\nBEEN TO THE\nSHRINE OF\nHUMILITY!", 
        "name": "BANTER", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "SEEK YE\nTHE HORN?", 
        "question_no_answer": "OH.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "ASK DEMITRY!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A THIN SKELETON.", 
        "health": "'BOUT THE SAME\nAS YESTERDAY.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I RATTLE\nMY BONES.", 
        "keyword_1": "BONES", 
        "keyword_2": "HORN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "BONES, THEM\nBONES, THEM\nDRY BONES...", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE QUEEN OF\nLOVE HAS A LADY\nIN WAITING, SHE\nCAN TELL THEE\nMORE OF THE\nHORN!", 
        "name": "DEMITRY", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "ART THOU DEAD?", 
        "question_no_answer": "WATCH OUT\nFOR NATE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "AH, TOO BAD!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "RATTLING BONES.", 
        "health": "HAUNTED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I HAUNT,\nAND I HAUNT,\nAND I HAUNT!", 
        "keyword_1": "HAUNT", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A HAUNTING JOB\nTAKES MORE THAN\nA LIFETIME, IT\nTAKES FOREVER!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "YES, I HAVE BEEN\nTO THE SHRINE,\nIT LIES ON THE\nNORTH BANK IN\nTHE ISLE OF THE\nABYSS!", 
        "name": "WIERDRUM", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A DUMPY GHOST.", 
        "health": "HIC...", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I WAS ONCE\nA POWERFUL\nMERCHANT!", 
        "keyword_1": "MERCH", 
        "keyword_2": "POWER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "MY WEALTH\nWAS BOUNDLESS,\nI HELD GREAT\nPOWER!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A PROUD SOUL\nSURELY KNOWS NOT\nIT'S WORTH!", 
        "name": "BOOZER", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "DOST THOU SEE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THE WORLD GOES\nON WITHOUT ME.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THE WORLD GOES\nON WITHOUT ME.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A FAT SKELETON.", 
        "health": "COULDN'T\nBE BETTER.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I RUN THIS SHOP.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHOP", 
        "keyword_2": "SPOIL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WHY, THE FOOD\nSHOP OF COURSE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "WELL, WE'RE\nEXPECTING MORE\nANY DAY!", 
        "name": "BULBOUS", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "CAN I INTEREST\nTHEE IN SOME\nRATIONS?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I SELL ONLY THE\nVERY BEST.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "HMMM, OUR STOCK\nSEEMS TO HAVE\nSPOILED....", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WEEPING\nSKELETON.", 
        "health": "BEEN BETTER.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I REGRET.", 
        "keyword_1": "REGRET", 
        "keyword_2": "HUMBLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I WAS PROUD,\nSTRIP THYSELF OF\nCONCEITS, ONLY\nTHE HUMBLE ARE\nPURE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE ROOT FROM\nWHICH ALL\nVIRTUES GROW!", 
        "name": "SPLOT", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nSEEK PURITY?", 
        "question_no_answer": "FOOL!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN ASK THE\nSNAKE OF THE\nRUNE AND STONE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BLUE GHOST.", 
        "health": "NOT WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I NOW TRY TO\nUNDERSTAND\nHUMILITY.", 
        "keyword_1": "HUMI", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE FIRST TEST\nOF A GREAT SOUL\nIS HUMILITY!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "ASK THE SNAKE OF\nTHE RUNE, JUST\nBEFORE IT\nSTRIKES!", 
        "name": "RUSKIN", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "DOST THOU SEEK\nTO KNOW\nHUMILITY?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A SHAME.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THOU SHALT NEED\nTHE RUNE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A MEAN LOOKING\nVIPER!", 
        "health": "BLOODTHIRSTY!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I BRING DEATH\nTO ALL LIFE IN\nMAGINCIA!", 
        "keyword_1": "STON", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THOSE WHO SEEK\nTHE BLACK STONE\nNEED ASK AT THE\nPUB IN BRITAIN!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE SACRED RUNE\nOF HUMILITY WAS\nBANISHED FROM\nTHIS CITY. ASK\nBARREN IN PAWS!", 
        "name": "NATE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A HORRIBLE\nGHASTLY DEVIL!", 
        "health": "DEVILISH!", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I WELCOME THEE\nTO MAGINCIA!\nPROUD CITY OF\nTHE HIGH SEAS!", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGIN", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "MAGINCIA FELL\nUNTO THE REALM\nOF DARKNESS FOR\nTHE FOUNDATION\nOF THEIR VIRTUE\nWAS ILL-PLACED\nIN PRIDE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "VIRTUEBANE", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "ART THOU PROUD?", 
        "question_no_answer": "AH.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A VERY\nBIG GUARD.", 
        "health": "EXCELLENT.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM THE CHIEF\nGUARD IN THE\nVILLAGE OF PAWS!", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "TROUB", 
        "keyword_response_1": "PAWS IS A GREAT\nVILLAGE AND WE\nKEEP IT SAFE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "PIRATES COME\nFROM AN ISLE TO\nTHE EAST!", 
        "name": "WILMOORE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nMEAN TO\nCAUSE TROUBLE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN THOU HAD\nBEST LEAVE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TOUGH GIRL.", 
        "health": "RIGHT GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM THE\nSTABLE HAND.", 
        "keyword_1": "STABLE", 
        "keyword_2": "SMITH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I SAW THE WAY YA\nDEALT WITH OL'\nRED EYE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE TALKING\nHORSE!", 
        "name": "FRANCESCA", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "YA HAVEN'T COME\nTO STEAL A HORSE\nI HOPE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN MUST BE\nTO SEE SMITH!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WELL THE MASTER\nAIN'T GONNA LIKE\nTHAT MUCH!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL\nBURLY MAN.", 
        "health": "FINE, THANKS.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I'M A\nLUMBERJACK, YA.", 
        "keyword_1": "LUMBER", 
        "keyword_2": "AXE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WIT' MY AXE, I\nCAN CHOP'M DOWN\nQUICK, YA.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "IT'S A BIG\nAXE, YA.", 
        "name": "SVEN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART YA A\nLUMBERJACK?", 
        "question_no_answer": "BUILD UP THOSE\nARMS, YA!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD FOR\nYOU, YA.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A MAN OF\nMANY YEARS.", 
        "health": "WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I'VE BEEN NEAR\nTHE CODEX!", 
        "keyword_1": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "ITS SECRETS\nARE BOUNDLESS!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A THREE PART KEY\nAND A WORD OF\nPASSAGE ARE\nNEEDED TO ENTER\nTHE CHAMBER. ASK\nMY BROTHER\nBEYOND LOCK LAKE\nOF THE WORD!", 
        "name": "ZAIR THE WISE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "SEEN IT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "SEEK IT!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WOW!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A VERY\nLARGE WOMAN.", 
        "health": "STRONGER\nEVERY DAY!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM THE BARMAID\nI SERVE THE ALE!", 
        "keyword_1": "ALE", 
        "keyword_2": "BREW", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WE HAVE THE\nFINEST BREW IN\nBRITANNIA!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "WE SERVE ONLY\nFOLLEY ON TAP!", 
        "name": "SAL", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nFAVOR FOLLEY?", 
        "question_no_answer": "TOO BAD,\nIT'S THE BEST!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "A GREAT MUG IF I\nMAY SAY SO!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A YOUNG MAGE!", 
        "health": "FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEEK THE\nWISDOM OF MAGIC.", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGIC", 
        "keyword_2": "MASTER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "MY MASTER KNOWS\nTHE GATE TRAVEL\nSPELL!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "MY MASTER IS\nMENTORIAN.", 
        "name": "JINGLES", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nKNOW HIM?", 
        "question_no_answer": "HE LIVES IN A\nHIDDEN VILLAGE\nIN LOCK LAKE\nREACHABLE ONLY\nBY SHIP, ASK OF\nTHE GATE SPELL!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL MUSCULAR\nKNIGHT.", 
        "health": "TIRED AND\nHUNGRY BUT\nALWAYS FAITHFUL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SERVE\nLORD BRITISH.", 
        "keyword_1": "FAITH", 
        "keyword_2": "QUEST", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I QUEST ALWAYS\nFOR BRITANNIA!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "MY QUEST IS TO\nDEFEAT THE EVILS\nOF THE WORLD.", 
        "name": "SIR HOBIE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "'TIS THY QUEST\nALSO?", 
        "question_no_answer": "A SHAME IT IS!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WE ARE AS ONE.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SMALL DRUID.", 
        "health": "A BIT HUNGRY.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM HERE TO\nBUY FOOD.", 
        "keyword_1": "FOOD", 
        "keyword_2": "RATION", 
        "keyword_response_1": "YES, I HEAR THEY\nHAVE THE BEST\nRATIONS HERE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "RATIONS ARE USED\nIN DUNGEONS.", 
        "name": "DAMSEL", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU TRAVEL\nIN THE DEPTHS?", 
        "question_no_answer": "PROBABLY A WIMP.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "IN THE GREAT\nCASTLE THERE IS\nA SECRET\nENTRANCE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A MEEK SHEPHERD.", 
        "health": "FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I JUST SIT HERE.", 
        "keyword_1": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "AROUND THERE IN\nTHE NOOK OF THE\nMOUNTAINS!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "WHEATPIN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU LOOKING\nFOR SOMETHING?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I SEE.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHAT?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A HOODED RANGER.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I TRAVEL\nTHE LAND.", 
        "keyword_1": "LAND", 
        "keyword_2": "RUNE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "BRITANNIA.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SEARCH THE\nHILLS IN THE\nSOUTH-EAST\nCORNER OF TOWN!", 
        "name": "BARREN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU DIM?", 
        "question_no_answer": "WE SHALL SEE.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I THOUGHT SO.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SMALL GIRL.", 
        "health": "GOOD, THANKS.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "WHAT'S A JOB?", 
        "keyword_1": "A", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "PIX", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "AND THEE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "TOO BAD.", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WISE LORD.", 
        "health": "I AM FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM THE KEEPER.", 
        "keyword_1": "KEEPER", 
        "keyword_2": "MYSTIC", 
        "keyword_response_1": "OF WHAT I\nCANNOT SAY!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "MYSTICS CAN BE\nFOUND BY AN\nEIGHT PARTS\nAVATAR!", 
        "name": "SIR SIMON", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU\nATTAINED\nENLIGHTENMENT IN\nALL EIGHT\nVIRTUES?", 
        "question_no_answer": "ALAS.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THE MYSTIC\nARMOUR LIES IN\nTHE CENTRE OF\nTHE OAK GROVE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WISE LADY.", 
        "health": "WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM THE KEEPER.", 
        "keyword_1": "KEEPER", 
        "keyword_2": "MYSTIC", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I CANNOT SAY.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "MYSTICS CAN BE\nFOUND BY AN\nEIGHT PARTS\nAVATAR!", 
        "name": "LADY TESSA", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU\nATTAINED\nENLIGHTENMENT IN\nALL EIGHT\nVIRTUES?", 
        "question_no_answer": "ALAS.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THE MYSTIC\nWEAPONS LIE IN\nTHE TRAINING\nROOM OF SERPENT\nCASTLE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SHORT JESTER.", 
        "health": "JOLLY GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM HERE TO\nSERVE THEE.", 
        "keyword_1": "SERVE", 
        "keyword_2": "DANCE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WELL, I CAN\nDANCE AND SING!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "AND SING,\nTRA LA LA...", 
        "name": "ASEMLY", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOES THAT\nINTEREST THEE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "WELL THEN, I\nGUESS I'M NO\nHELP AT ALL\nTHEN.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SINGING BARD.", 
        "health": "QUITE WELL\nINDEED!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SING OF\nBRITANNIA.", 
        "keyword_1": "BRIT", 
        "keyword_2": "EARTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "BRITANNIA IS A\nLAND SO FAIR,\nTO OTHER LANDS I\nWOULD NOT DARE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I HOPE SOMEDAY\nTHOU MAY RETURN!", 
        "name": "LITTLE JON", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "I HEAR THAT THOU\nART FROM ANOTHER\nWORLD?", 
        "question_no_answer": "JUST A RUMOR.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHAT IS\nIT CALLED?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WHITE\nSTALLION.", 
        "health": "GOOD, GOOD.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "OH, NOT MUCH.", 
        "keyword_1": "A", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "A", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "SMITH", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A MEAN LOOKING\nGUARD.", 
        "health": "WHAT'S IT TO\nYA SCUMPUPPY!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "WE GUARD THE\nBRIDGE SLIME!", 
        "keyword_1": "BRIDGE", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THIS BRIDGE YA\nSTUPID JERK!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "ROOFUS", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU A\nWISE &##!?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN JUST\nBUZZ OFF!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THOU HAD BEST\nDITCH IT THEN!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL,\nMUSCULAR,\nIMPRESSIVE\nGUARD.", 
        "health": "VERY HUNGRY!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM A GUARD.", 
        "keyword_1": "GUARD", 
        "keyword_2": "HUNGER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I GUARD\nTHE CITY!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "YES, I AM\nVERY HUNGRY!", 
        "name": "RANKBREATH", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU HERE\nTO FEED ME?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN THOU HAD\nBETTER RUN!!!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I AM GRATEFUL.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 20
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SCRUFFY\nSAILOR.", 
        "health": "SALTY.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM A SAILOR!", 
        "keyword_1": "SAIL", 
        "keyword_2": "LIFE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "OH, A SAILOR'S\nLIFE IS THE LIFE\nFOR ME,", 
        "keyword_response_2": "AS I SAIL ACROSS\nTHE BOUNDING\nSEA!", 
        "name": "SAILOR", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "THE REST?", 
        "question_no_answer": "OH.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "AND NEVER EVER\nEVER DO I WORRY\n'BOUT THE\nWEATHER, FOR THE\nWEATHER NEVER\nEVER DID A THING\nFOR ME!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL SAILOR.", 
        "health": "GOOD ENOUGH, EH!", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "I'M A\nPIRATE MATEY!", 
        "keyword_1": "PIRA", 
        "keyword_2": "RAID", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WE RAID THE\nCOASTS OF\nBRITANNIA, FUN\nEH!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "PILLAGE\nAND BURN!", 
        "name": "SILVER JOHN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU\nA PIRATE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THOU HAD BEST\nLEAVE THIS PLACE\n'FORE THERE'S\nANY TROUBLE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD MATEY!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A NIMBLE THIEF.", 
        "health": "AS GOOD AS\nI NEED BE!", 
        "humility_question": true, 
        "job": "WHAT'S IT\nTO THEE?", 
        "keyword_1": "THIEF", 
        "keyword_2": "CLEVER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "YEA, AND\nCLEVER TOO.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THOU DOST ASK\nTOO MANY\nQUESTIONS!", 
        "name": "SLYSAM", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU\nA THIEF?", 
        "question_no_answer": "JUST AS I\nTHOUGHT", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "OH, I'D BETTER\nWATCH OUT!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 10
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SOLEMN RANGER.", 
        "health": "O.K.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I TRAVEL.", 
        "keyword_1": "TRAVEL", 
        "keyword_2": "SKULL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE LANDS OF\nBRITANNIA.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "BE WARNED THAT\nIF THOU DOST\nEVER USE THE\nSKULL, EXCEPT TO\nDESTROY IT, ALL\nTHY VIRTUES WILL\nBE LOST!", 
        "name": "RAGNAR", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU HERE\nLOOKING FOR\nINFORMATION?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THEN BUZZ OFF.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "ON WHAT?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 10
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SLINKY MAGE.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM A SORCERESS", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGIC", 
        "keyword_2": "SLEEP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "HOW ABOUT THE\nSLEEP SPELL...\nSLEEP...\nSLEEP....", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A SLEEP SPELL\nREQUIRES BUT ONE\nPART SILK!\nSLEEP...\nSLEEP...\nSLEEP...", 
        "name": "SEANNA", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "MY DEAR FRIEND,\nMAY I HELP YOU?", 
        "question_no_answer": "AH", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "HOW ABOUT WITH\nTHY MAGIC?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SNEAKY THIEF!", 
        "health": "VERY WELL!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "AT THY SERVICE!", 
        "keyword_1": "SERV", 
        "keyword_2": "HYTH", 
        "keyword_response_1": "HOW ABOUT\nINFORMATION?", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE DUNGEON\nHYTHLOTH CAN\nONLY BE REACHED\nBY A SECRET\nENTRANCE IN THE\nGREAT CASTLE.", 
        "name": "JEREMY JAMES\nSCIRLOCK", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU SEEK A\nSPECIAL DUNGEON?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I CANNOT\nHELP THEE.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHICH?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A MAGE DRESSED\nALL IN BLACK.", 
        "health": "DARK INDEED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I USE\nBLACK MAGIC!", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGIC", 
        "keyword_2": "MIX", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I CAST POWERFUL\nMAGIC MISSILE\nSPELLS.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "TRY ONE BLACK\nPEARL AND ONE\nPART SULPHUROUS\nASH!", 
        "name": "STARLIGHT", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU?", 
        "question_no_answer": "TOO BAD.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THOU SHOULD TRY\nMY MIX OF\nREAGENTS!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BIG FAT TROLL.", 
        "health": "SHOVE IT!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "AW, BUZZ OFF!", 
        "keyword_1": "IT", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THY FACE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "BRIGANT", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "DID THOU\nHEAR ME?", 
        "question_no_answer": "I SAID SHOVE IT!", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN DO IT!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 80
    }, 
    {
        "description": "AN UGLY ORC!", 
        "health": "GOOD'N SMELLY.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SMUGGLE BLACK\nMARKET ITEMS.", 
        "keyword_1": "ITEMS", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "MAGIC KEYS,\nMAGIC GEMS,\nTHAT SORT\nOF THING.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "BORIS", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "DOST THOU NEED\nSUCH AN ITEM?", 
        "question_no_answer": "AH WELL,\nMAYBE NEXT TIME.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I JUST GAVE THE\nGUILD SHOP A NEW\nSUPPLY!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TOWERING\nWIZARD.", 
        "health": "ADEQUATE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I MUST\nWARN THEE!", 
        "keyword_1": "WARN", 
        "keyword_2": "DOOM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "TO STEP INTO\nTHOSE WOODS WILL\nSEAL THY DOOM!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "IN THERE LIES\nTHE DARK SIDE,\nENTER NOT!", 
        "name": "IGNAP", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "SHALT THOU\nGO ON?", 
        "question_no_answer": "WISE DECISION!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "EVIL SHALL\nCONSUME THEE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL PIRATE\nWITH A GREEN\nBEARD!", 
        "health": "JOLLY GOOD MATE!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I'M BUYING\nARMOUR FOR MY\nCREW!", 
        "keyword_1": "ARMOUR", 
        "keyword_2": "NOWHER", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I HOPE TO GET\nSOME MAGICAL\nPLATE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "OH, I SEE.", 
        "name": "GREEN BEARD", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "KNOW WHERE TO\nBUY MYSTIC\nARMOUR?", 
        "question_no_answer": "WISH I DID!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHERE?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A PLUMP\nMERCHANT.", 
        "health": "GREAT!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SELL WINE!", 
        "keyword_1": "WINE", 
        "keyword_2": "VINTAG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I HAVE SOME\nGOOD VINTAGES.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I OWN MY OWN\nVINEYARDS, THEY\nARE ON AN ISLE\nNORTHEAST OF\nHERE!", 
        "name": "MARSOR", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nLIKE WINE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "DON'T KNOW\nWHAT THOU\nART MISSING!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "AH, THEN JOIN ME\nIN A GLASS!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A JOLLY\nOLD SOUL.", 
        "health": "JOLLY GOOD,\nTHANKS.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM A TINKER\nBY TRADE.", 
        "keyword_1": "TINKER", 
        "keyword_2": "MACHIN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I CREATE\nPROJECTILE\nMACHINERY.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "PRIMARILY\nSHIP CANNONS!", 
        "name": "DANCEK", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU OWN\nA SHIP!", 
        "question_no_answer": "THOU REALLY\nSHOULD GET ONE!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD ODDS I\nBUILT THE\nCANNONS!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A COWERING MAN.", 
        "health": "O.K. FOR NOW.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM HIDING.", 
        "keyword_1": "HIDE", 
        "keyword_2": "SOME", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I KNOW SOMETHING\nOTHERS WANT!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I... I...", 
        "name": "SNIFLET", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU\nPROMISE TO USE\nIT ONLY TO AID\nTHE POWERS OF\nGOOD?", 
        "question_no_answer": "OH, NO.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THE LIGHTER THAN\nAIR DEVICE THAT\nWAS STOLEN LIES\nNEAR THE DUNGEON\nHYTHLOTH!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL MAGE.", 
        "health": "WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "WE WELCOME THEE\nTO VESPER.", 
        "keyword_1": "VESPER", 
        "keyword_2": "WELCOM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "YES, VESPER IS A\nFAIR VILLAGE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "WELCOME,\nUNTO VESPER!", 
        "name": "TWIN GATES", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU COME\nA LONG WAY?", 
        "question_no_answer": "WE ARE HONORED\nBY THE VISIT OF\nONE ON THE\nQUEST!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WE ARE HONORED\nBY THE VISIT OF\nONE ON THE\nQUEST!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A HULK.", 
        "health": "UG, ME TOUGH!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "UG, ME TOUGH!", 
        "keyword_1": "TOUGH", 
        "keyword_2": "UG", 
        "keyword_response_1": "UG, ME TOUGH!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "ME TOUGH!", 
        "name": "GUARD", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "UG, THEE TOUGH?", 
        "question_no_answer": "UG, ME TOUGH!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "UG, THEE TOUGH!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A MEEK SHEPHERD.", 
        "health": "WELL FOR NOW.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I CAN HELP THEE!", 
        "keyword_1": "HELP", 
        "keyword_2": "SKUL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I KNOW OF THE\nSKULL OF MONDAIN\nTHE WIZARD!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "TO USE IT FOR\nANY REASON IS A\nSIGN OF GREAT\nEVIL, AND NO\nVIRTUE!", 
        "name": "SERVILE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU\nHEARD OF IT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "IT IS AN\nEVIL ARTIFACT!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "IT IS AN\nEVIL ARTIFACT!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SHORT, ROTUND\nMAN WITH A HAT\nAND VEST.", 
        "health": "I AM FINE,\nTHANK THEE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "TRAVELING DAN,\nTHE TINKER MAN.", 
        "keyword_1": "TINKER", 
        "keyword_2": "TRAVEL", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I AM HERE TO\nREPAIR GOODS AT\nTHE GUILD SHOP.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I KNOW THE WORLD\nIS ROUND!", 
        "name": "TRAVELING DAN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "BEEN TO THE\nGUILD SHOP?", 
        "question_no_answer": "BEST PRICES!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GREAT SELECTION!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A STURDY\nPEASANT.", 
        "health": "I'M POOPED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM A SERF.", 
        "keyword_1": "SERF", 
        "keyword_2": "WORK", 
        "keyword_response_1": "SERFS WORK HARD\nFOR LITTLE PAY!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "I WORK THE\nFIELDS FOR MY\nMASTER!", 
        "name": "BALTHASAR", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU HAVE\nA MASTER?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THOU ART LUCKY\nINDEED!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "I HOPE HE OR SHE\nIS A KIND ONE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SMALL MAN.", 
        "health": "I AM\nFULLY HEALED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEEK HUMILITY.", 
        "keyword_1": "HUMI", 
        "keyword_2": "PRIDE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "WHEN THE 3\nPRINCIPLES OF\nVIRTUE COMBINE\nIN EIGHT WAYS\nPRIDE HAS NO\nVIRTUE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "TO BE PROUD IS\nNOT A VIRTUE,\nAND SO MAGINCIA\nWAS DESTROYED!\nHUMILITY IS THE\nVIRTUE THAT\nREMAINS!", 
        "name": "PLAIN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SLENDER\nSHEPHERDESS.", 
        "health": "I AM FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SEEK THE\nSHRINE.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_2": "HUMILI", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE SHRINE\nOF HUMILITY!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE SHRINE LIES\nON THE NORTH\nBANK OF THE ISLE\nOF THE ABYSS AND\nIS GUARDED BY\nENDLESS HOARDS\nOF DAEMONS!", 
        "name": "SIMPLE", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "KNOW THE ISLE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "SOUTHEAST OF\nBRITANNIA!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A FAIR WOMAN.", 
        "health": "I AM DOING WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I DO HUMBLE\nWORKS.", 
        "keyword_1": "WORKS", 
        "keyword_2": "MANTRA", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I CAN HELP THEE\nWITH THE MANTRA!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SINCE HUMILITY\nIS THE OPPOSITE\nOF PRIDE, SO IS\nITS MANTRA!", 
        "name": "GEM", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "KNOW YE THE\nMANTRA OF PRIDE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "WHEN THOU DOST,\nREVERSE IT!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THEN REVERSE IT\nFOR HUMILITY!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WISE SHEPHERD.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM BUT A\nHUMBLE SHEPHERD.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHEP", 
        "keyword_2": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I AM ON A\nPILGRIMAGE UNTO\nTHE SHRINE OF\nHUMILITY!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "IT IS ON THE\nDARK ISLAND!", 
        "name": "JOSEPH", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DID THOU KNOW\nTHAT THERE IS NO\nSHRINE OF PRIDE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "PRIDE IS NOT A\nVIRTUE OF THE\nAVATAR!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "VERY GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BEAUTIFUL\nAND IMPRESSIVE\nGUARD.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL\nENOUGH!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SHALL WARN\nTHEE AGAINST\nTAKING THIS\nGOLD!", 
        "keyword_1": "GOLD", 
        "keyword_2": "WARN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "IT IS NOT THINE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "IT IS NOT THINE!", 
        "name": "FRIDAY", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU INTEND\nTO TAKE IT?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THAT IS GOOD.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THAT WOULD NOT\nREFLECT WELL\nUPON THY\nVIRTUES!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SOLEMN RANGER.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I TEACH OF\nTHE SHRINES.", 
        "keyword_1": "SHRINE", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "ONE >MUST< VISIT\nEACH SHRINE FOR\n1, 2 & 3 CYCLES\nEACH FOR THY\nPATHS TO BE\nCLEAR!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "RANDAL", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU VISIT\nTHEM OFTEN?", 
        "question_no_answer": "MAKE THAT THE\nFIRST GOAL ALONG\nTHY PATH TO\nAVATARHOOD!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "VERY GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WISE MAN.", 
        "health": "WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I GIVE WISE\nCOUNSEL.", 
        "keyword_1": "COUN", 
        "keyword_2": "VIRTUE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "STRIVE YE TO\nKNOW AND\nDEVELOP THE\nVIRTUE WITHIN\nTHEE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE SEER\nHAWKWIND SHOULD\nBE CONSULTED\n>OFTEN< FOR HE\nCAN SEE WITHIN\nTHEE!", 
        "name": "DIRGEN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THOU SHALT\nSURELY STRAY\nFROM THE PATH!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A FUNNY JESTER.", 
        "health": "I'VE A\nSLIGHT TICKLE!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "THOU THINKS\nI'M FUNNY!", 
        "keyword_1": "FUNNY", 
        "keyword_2": "NATE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I DARE THEE TO\nASK ME ABOUT\nNATE THE SNAKE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "WELL, IT'S A\nLONG STORY AND\nWE HAVEN'T THE\nTIME.", 
        "name": "SHAZBOT", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "DON'T THOU?", 
        "question_no_answer": "AH, TOO BAD, I\nTHOUGHT I WAS.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WELL GOOD, I\nTRY TO BE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SLENDER YOUTH.", 
        "health": "I AM VERY\nPOWERFUL!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM AN\nAPPRENTICE MAGE!", 
        "keyword_1": "MAGE", 
        "keyword_2": "CALUMN", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I AM THE\nCALUMNY'S\nFAVORITE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "HE LIVES IN YEW!", 
        "name": "FLATBUSH", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU\nBEEN TO YEW?", 
        "question_no_answer": "CALUMNY KNOWS\nTHE QUICKNESS\nSPELL! SEEK\nHIM OUT!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "CALUMNY KNOWS\nTHE QUICKNESS\nSPELL!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A BOLD PALADIN.", 
        "health": "I AM FULLY\nHEALED!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I TRAVEL THESE\nFAIR LANDS TO\nSPREAD THE\nVIRTUES!", 
        "keyword_1": "VIRTUE", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "TO KNOW THY\nPROGRESS ON THE\nPATHS OF VIRTUE\nONE >MUST< VISIT\nTHE SEER\nHAWKWIND OFTEN!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "CORKRIN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nDO THIS?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THOU MUST OR\nTHOU MAY STRAY!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL\nNIMBLE MAN.", 
        "health": "I AM VERY WELL!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM A THIEF, I\nLIKE TO BORROW!", 
        "keyword_1": "BORROW", 
        "keyword_2": "HORSES", 
        "keyword_response_1": "MY FAVORITE\nTHINGS TO BORROW\nARE HORSES!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "YOU CAN STEAL\nHORSES IN THE\nTOWNE PAWS!", 
        "name": "DYKA", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU\nA THIEF?", 
        "question_no_answer": "LIKELY, THOU\nART A WIMP!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WATCH OUT FOR\nTHE BULL IN THE\nCORRAL!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SMALL BOY.", 
        "health": "I AM FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I KNOW HOW TO\nENTER THE ABYSS!", 
        "keyword_1": "ABYSS", 
        "keyword_2": "SHIP", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE ABYSS\nMAY ONLY\nBE APPROACHED\nBY SHIP!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE SHIP MUST\nHAVE A MAGICALLY\nSTRENGTHENED\nHULL!", 
        "name": "ALLEN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU SUCH\nA VESSEL?", 
        "question_no_answer": "ASK BLISSFUL OF\nTHE ABYSS.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "ASK BLISSFUL OF\nTHE ABYSS.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SMALL DRUID.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "WELCOME TO COVE,\nTHE HIDDEN CITY\nOF WISDOM.", 
        "keyword_1": "WISDOM", 
        "keyword_2": "PEACE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "HEREIN IS FOUND\nMUCH WISDOM AND\nPEACE.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "FIND PEACE IN\nOUR SHRINE.", 
        "name": "FRONTIS", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "ART THOU WELL?", 
        "question_no_answer": "VISIT OUR\nHEALERS, I AM\nSURE THEY CAN\nHELP THEE!", 
        "question_trigger": "health", 
        "question_yes_answer": "VERY GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "AN OLD HERMIT.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I AM A RECLUSE.", 
        "keyword_1": "RECLU", 
        "keyword_2": "STONE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I HAVE WITHDRAWN\nFROM SOCIETY.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "ONLY THE GHOST\nOF ISAAC WHO\nHAUNTS THE INN\nAT SKARA BRAE\nCAN TELL THEE.", 
        "name": "SLOVEN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "HAST THOU\nSEEN HIM?", 
        "question_no_answer": "STAY AT THE INN\nUNTIL HE SHOWS\nHIMSELF!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "ASK HIM!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL WIZARD.", 
        "health": "WELL INDEED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I STUDY THE\nMAGICAL ARTS.", 
        "keyword_1": "ARTS", 
        "keyword_2": "GATE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THERE IS TRUTH\nIN MAGIC!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "SINCE THOU DOST\nBEAR THE ANKH I\nSHALL TELL THEE.\nA GATE SPELL\nREQUIRES ASH,\nPEARL, AND\nMANDRAKE ROOT!", 
        "name": "MENTORIAN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nDISAGREE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WELL THEN,\nBEGONE!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SHINING ANKH!", 
        "health": "BRIGHT.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I RESONATE\nWITH THOUGHTS.", 
        "keyword_1": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_2": "CHAMB", 
        "keyword_response_1": "TO ENTER THE\nCODEX CHAMBER.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "ONE MUST BE 8\nPARTS AVATAR,\nHAVE THE KEY OF\n3 PARTS, THE\nWORD OF PASSAGE\nAND KNOW THE\nPURE AXIOM!", 
        "name": "THE ANKH", 
        "pronoun": "IT", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nSEEK HELP?", 
        "question_no_answer": "OH.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "WHAT ARE THY\nTHOUGHTS?", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A STRANGELY\nFAMILIAR BARD.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I PLAY OF LOVE.", 
        "keyword_1": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_2": "PROBLE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I LIGHT A\nCANDLE TO OUR\nLOVE, IN LOVE\nOUR PROBLEMS\nDISAPPEAR.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "BUT ALL IN ALL\nWE SOON DISCOVER\nTHAT ONE AND ONE\nIS ALL WE LONG\nTO HEAR!", 
        "name": "PAUL", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU\nLISTEN?", 
        "question_no_answer": "TOO BAD.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "ABOUT LOVE.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SINGER.", 
        "health": "FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SING OF\nTHE CHILDREN.", 
        "keyword_1": "CHILD", 
        "keyword_2": "WORLD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "ALL ROUND THE\nWORLD, LITTLE\nCHILDREN BEING\nBORN TO THE\nWORLD.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "GOT TO GIVE THEM\nALL WE CAN 'TIL\nTHE QUEST IS\nWON, THEN WILL\nTHE WORK BE\nDONE!", 
        "name": "LINDA", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "WILT THOU HELP?", 
        "question_no_answer": "HMM.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "TEACH THEM\nSONGS OF JOY!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A MYSTICAL\nWIZARD.", 
        "health": "FINE.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I USE MAGIC.", 
        "keyword_1": "STONE", 
        "keyword_2": "GATE", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE BLACK STONE\nIS CAUGHT IN A\nMOON GATE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "STAND WHERE THE\nGATE OF BOTH\nMOONS DARK SHALL\nAPPEAR. SEARCH\nWHEN THE MOONS\nGO DARK!", 
        "name": "MERLIN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU\nSTUDY MAGIC?", 
        "question_no_answer": "TOO BAD.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "BEST OF LUCK\nWITH THY\nSTUDIES!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "AN OLD DRUID.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I TEACH\nTHE RELATION.", 
        "keyword_1": "RELAT", 
        "keyword_2": "A", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THERE ARE\nEIGHT POSSIBLE\nCOMBINATIONS OF\nTRUTH, LOVE AND\nCOURAGE. EACH\nOF THE EIGHT\nVIRTUES IS ONE\nOF THOSE\nCOMBINATIONS!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "A", 
        "name": "DRACONIAN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "KNEW YE THIS?", 
        "question_no_answer": "LEARN THE TOWNS\nAND CASTLES!", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "VERY GOOD!", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A MAJESTIC\nSEAHORSE!", 
        "health": "I AM DOING WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I KNOW MUCH\nOF THE CODEX!", 
        "keyword_1": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_2": "ABYSS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE SHRINE ANKH\nKNOWS HOW TO\nENTER THE\nCHAMBER OF THE\nCODEX!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "MEDITATE AT\nTHE SHRINES\nOF HONESTY,\nCOMPASSION AND\nVALOR FOR 3\nCYCLES TO KNOW\nHOW TO ENTER!", 
        "name": "BLISSFUL", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WISE MAN.", 
        "health": "I AM OLD\nBUT STRONG!", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SPEAK OF LOVE.", 
        "keyword_1": "LOVE", 
        "keyword_2": "HEART", 
        "keyword_response_1": "IN LOVE,\nALL LIFE'S\nCONTRADICTIONS\nDISSOLVE AND\nDISAPPEAR.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "CARRY LOVE\nWITHIN IT!", 
        "name": "RABINDRANATH\nTAGORE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "DOST THOU SEEK\nTO CARRY LOVE IN\nTHY HEART?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THOU ART A FOOL.", 
        "question_trigger": "job", 
        "question_yes_answer": "THOU ART A\nGOOD SOUL.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "AN OLD DRUID.", 
        "health": "I AM WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I SIT AND WATCH\nTHE RIVER.", 
        "keyword_1": "RIVER", 
        "keyword_2": "WORD", 
        "keyword_response_1": "IT FLOWS\nENDLESSLY.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE KINGS OF THE\nCASTLES WHICH\nREPRESENT THE\nTHREE PRINCIPLES\nOF VIRTUE EACH\nKNOW BUT ONE\nSYLLABLE OF THE\nWORD OF PASSAGE!", 
        "name": "BROTHER ZAIR", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "AGREE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "INDEED.", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 1", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A SLENDER MAGE.", 
        "health": "WELL INDEED.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I KNOW OF\nTHE CODEX.", 
        "keyword_1": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_2": "COMB", 
        "keyword_response_1": "ONE MUST KNOW\nTHE COMBINATION\nOF THE THREE\nPRINCIPLES OF\nVIRTUE!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE COMBINATION\nOF THE THREE\nPRINCIPLES OF\nVIRTUE EQUALS\nTHE MEASURE OF\nTIME AND SPACE!", 
        "name": "SPELLBIND", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A TALL MAGE.", 
        "health": "QUITE WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I STUDY THE\n'ONE' THING THAT\nIS THE SECRET TO\nTHE CODEX!", 
        "keyword_1": "STUDY", 
        "keyword_2": "CODEX", 
        "keyword_response_1": "I STUDY OF\nTHE CODEX!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE ONE PURE\nAXIOM IS MORE\nENDLESS THAN THE\nCHANGING TIDES,\nMORE ETERNAL\nTHAN DAY AND\nNIGHT!", 
        "name": "SHAMAN", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A FAIR\nSORCERESS.", 
        "health": "WELL ENOUGH.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I PONDER THE KEY\nTO THE AXIOM.", 
        "keyword_1": "KEY", 
        "keyword_2": "AXIOM", 
        "keyword_response_1": "TO THE AXIOM.", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE 1 PURE AXIOM\nENCOMPASSES\nALL THINGS.", 
        "name": "CHARM", 
        "pronoun": "SHE", 
        "question": "KNOW YE WHAT\nTHEY ARE?", 
        "question_no_answer": "THE TRUTHS OF\nTHE UNIVERSE,\nTHE LOVE OF THE\nHEART, AND THE\nCOURAGE OF THE\nSOUL!", 
        "question_trigger": "keyword 2", 
        "question_yes_answer": "GOOD.", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }, 
    {
        "description": "A WISE MAGE.", 
        "health": "WELL.", 
        "humility_question": false, 
        "job": "I TEACH OF\nTHE AXIOM!", 
        "keyword_1": "AXIOM", 
        "keyword_2": "PARTS", 
        "keyword_response_1": "THE WHOLE OF THE\nAXIOM IS GREATER\nTHAN ALL ITS\nPARTS!", 
        "keyword_response_2": "THE MEASURE OF\nUNENDING LOVE,\nTHE LIMITLESS\nCOURAGE NEEDED\nTO FACE ALL\nOBSTACLES,THE\nTRUTH WHICH\nENCOMPASSES ALL\nTHINGS!", 
        "name": "CIRCE", 
        "pronoun": "HE", 
        "question": "A", 
        "question_no_answer": "A", 
        "question_trigger": null, 
        "question_yes_answer": "A", 
        "turns_away_prob": 0
    }
]
